<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/feeds/pugpig/rss.xml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/feeds/pugpig/rss.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/feeds/pugpig/latest-articles/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>To Counter China, Out-Invent It</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-12/counter-china-out-invent-it</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;China’s economic strategy is no secret. In the short term, Beijing will grow the country’s economy by manufacturing and exporting cheap, globally competitive goods. Over the longer term, it will build the capital, infrastructure, and expertise necessary to make the country an innovation powerhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China is not the first to adopt this strategy. The same measures powered the rise of countries such as Germany, France, and Japan over the last 70 years. And even then they caused considerable trade friction with the United States. Washington accused all three of those countries of unfair trade and monetary policies—Germany and France in the 1970s and Japan in the 1980s. Recent U.S. administrations have accused China of the same. But this time around, the tension is more concerning. China is much more populous than Germany, France, or Japan, and its economy could easily become the world’s largest. Beijing also projects influence beyond its borders, sharing technology with smaller countries and endeavoring to create a set of close trade and investment relationships—ones that may one day be based on Chinese renminbi instead of the U.S. dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his second term, President Barack Obama tried to pressure China to change its behavior through alliances and international cooperation, most notably in the form of a trans-Pacific trading bloc. More recently, President Donald Trump has taken a confrontational approach and imposed tariffs on Chinese goods. Trump has labeled China a “currency manipulator” and seeks to end intellectual property theft and narrow the U.S.-Chinese trade deficit by waging a trade war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Trump’s sights are set on outdated threats. China’s economic strategy has already mostly succeeded. As a result, Beijing hasn’t artificially depressed the value of its currency in over a decade, and it has begun to improve intellectual property protection as a way to encourage local innovation. The bilateral trade deficit, while asymmetrical, is a bad reason to launch a trade war. There is no need to balance trade with any single trading partner, only to make sure the overall balance doesn’t become too lopsided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest threat from China is both much more serious and considerably easier to address than any the Trump administration has identified. Through government-led investment in research and development, China is poised to become the global leader in scientific and technological innovation in the near future, displacing the United States from a position it has held for 70 years. China’s rise in this area will not only threaten U.S. national security but deprive the U.S. economy of a great many good jobs. Instead of sparring with China over trade, the United States should dramatically increase its own investment in research and development. Only by spurring domestic innovation can the United States counter China.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;THE REAL CHINESE THREAT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That China might one day lead the world in technological innovation would have seemed laughable a generation ago. The Cultural Revolution decimated higher education in China. For a decade beginning in 1966, authorities shuttered schools and universities, sent intellectuals to labor camps, and effectively suspended scientific research. The educational system was gradually restored under Deng Xiaoping, but only in the 1990s and the first decade of this century did investment in higher education produce significant progress in science and engineering. From 1990 to 2010, Chinese enrollment in higher education rose eightfold, and the number of college graduates exploded from 300,000 to nearly three million per year. Over the same time period, China’s share of total world higher educational enrollment increased from 6 to 17 percent. In 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2017/04/higher-education-in-china-has-boomed-in-the-last-decade&quot;&gt;eight million&lt;/a&gt; students graduated from Chinese universities. By comparison, roughly three million students graduated from U.S. universities that year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Nothing illustrates the power of technological innovation better than the last hundred years of U.S. history.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of scientific education in China can be debated, but the numbers cannot. In 1990, the United States graduated 20 times more science and engineering Ph.D.’s than did China. Just two decades later, China overtook the United States on that metric, minting 29,000 new Ph.D.’s in 2010 to the United States’ 25,000. Chinese universities are still weaker than their U.S. counterparts, but the gap is closing. Six Chinese universities now rank in the top 100 global universities, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times Higher Education&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/world-university-rankings&quot;&gt;ranking&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More scientists and more engineers add up, over time, to more innovation, especially when given adequate funding. Total &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/statistics/2018/nsb20181/&quot;&gt;worldwide spending&lt;/a&gt; on research and development ran about $2 trillion in 2015, the last year for which data are available. The United States accounted for roughly a quarter of that spending, down from 37 percent in 2000. China’s share was 21 percent of world R &amp;amp; D spending, or $408.8 billion, up from $33 billion in 2000. In cutting-edge fields such as synthetic biology, clean energy, and artificial intelligence, China has quickly become an important player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TECHNOLOGY IS POWER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing illustrates the power of technological innovation better than the last hundred years of U.S. history. In 1938, on the eve of World War II, U.S. federal and state governments together spent roughly 0.075 percent of GDP on scientific research, a miniscule amount. By 1944, federal and state (but mostly federal) governments were spending nearly 0.5 percent of GDP on science—a sevenfold increase that was used to develop radar systems, penicillin, and the atomic bomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trend continued into peacetime (and into the Cold War), as the U.S. government channeled public resources into scientific research on an entirely new scale. From 1940 to 1964, federal funding for research and development increased twentyfold. At its peak in the mid-1960s, this spending amounted to roughly two percent of GDP. Modern pharmaceuticals, microelectronics, digital computers, jet aircraft, satellites, GPS, the Internet, and much more resulted from this investment. New ideas that came out of government-funded R &amp;amp; D blossomed into iconic companies like IBM, AT&amp;amp;T, and Xerox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the late 1960s, government spending on research and development began a slow and steady decline. By the early 1980s, public spending on R &amp;amp; D had slipped to 1.2 percent of GDP and by 2017 it had fallen to just over 0.6 percent. Nine countries now outspend the United States on R &amp;amp; D, when measured as a share of GDP. The picture is slightly more complicated when private sector spending is taken into account, but the United States lags behind seven other countries in total public and private R &amp;amp; D spending. China still spends less than the United States—both in public spending and in combined public and private spending on R &amp;amp; D—but it is catching up fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The United States pioneered the fields of synthetic biology and hydrogen power, but both seem more likely to develop in China.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The private sector in the United States continues to innovate, but mostly in the kinds of software projects favored by modern venture capitalists. Outside of the life sciences, the private sector doesn’t spend much on attempting fundamental breakthroughs, such as finding new energy sources, because while new knowledge is great for the economy as a whole, it seldom pays off for the investors who fund the work. As a result, businesses have moved away from research that doesn’t have an immediate commercial application, precipitating a 60 percent decline in publications by corporate scientists between 1980 and the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the promising fields of synthetic biology and hydrogen power, for example, the private sector has largely avoided the kinds of long-term investments that spawned previous breakthroughs. The United States pioneered both fields, but they seem more likely to develop in China and other countries that offer them ample support. And by 2025, China will displace the United States as the world R &amp;amp; D leader in pharmaceuticals, according to a recent analysis of medical research published by &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Medical Association. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A BETTER STRATEGY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid being overtaken by China, the United States should increase federal government support for scientific research as well as efforts to translate that research into products and services that can be brought to market. Government R &amp;amp; D spending has a remarkably high rate of social return, meaning that the benefits are spread widely throughout society. Based on recent studies of government support for civilian- and military-oriented research in the United States, Europe, and New Zealand, we estimate that a federal government commitment of $100 billion per year to R &amp;amp; D would help create roughly four million good new jobs. The most productive use of such funding would be to upgrade the physical infrastructure that supports science, including new laboratories, expanded graduate programs, and incubators for developing capital-intensive technologies that may take a long time to perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, the government should look for productive ways to spread this investment around the country. Innovation increasingly takes place in a few highly concentrated hubs where talented people congregate—places such as Seattle, the San Francisco Bay Area, Los Angeles, Boston, New York City, and Washington, D.C. But with restrictive zoning and high housing prices, these hubs have become expensive and congested. Investing in places where land is cheap and people have the potential to become much more productive will help redress regional disparities in opportunity and employment, while at the same time building an advantage over international competitors by drawing more Americans into the scientific enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Jump-Starting-America-Breakthrough-Economic-American/dp/1541762487&quot;&gt;Jump-Starting America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, we identify 102 urban communities that are plausible next-generation tech hubs. Spread across 36 states in all regions of the country, these cities and towns have large populations, highly educated workers, and a low cost of living. Examples include Rochester, New York; Baton Rouge, Louisiana; and Topeka, Kansas. To turn these cities into tech hubs, the federal government should support collaboration between universities, private businesses, and local governments with the aim of making higher education more affordable, expanding practical and technical training, and creating pipelines from local educational institutions to employers. Together, these public-private consortiums could work to keep housing costs affordable by overhauling zoning law to allow for sufficient construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to counter China is to out-invent it—and to turn inventions into products and services that people around the world want to buy. The United States was once very good at this. China’s rise should remind the United States that it can and should renew its commitment to technological and scientific advancement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;JONATHAN GRUBER is Ford Professor of Economics at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIMON JOHNSON is Ronald A. Kurtz (1954) Professor of Entrepreneurship at the MIT Sloan School of Management. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, September 12, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Jonathan Gruber and Simon Johnson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-12/counter-china-out-invent-it</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/12/rsz_china_science.jpg?itok=_VNLsUxn</image>
 <media:description>A lab in Beijing, May 2017 - Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>Trump’s Trade War Ignores the Real Threat From Beijing</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T11:21:10-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Roots of Hindu Nationalism’s Triumph in India</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2019-09-11/roots-hindu-nationalisms-triumph-india</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;When Indians voted in parliamentary elections earlier this year, they did more than just elect a government. They also participated in the birth of India as a Hindu nation with a state to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India was established in 1947 as a pluralist nation, home to people of many religions, sects, and ethnicities. The country’s constitution provides no special claim over the state or its territory to any one of them—including the Hindus, who make up roughly 80 percent of the population. Moreover, Hindus themselves are hardly a monolith: they differ in the languages they speak, the beliefs they hold, the deities they worship, and the rituals and customs that shape their lives. As a result, Hindus have historically not thought of themselves as a single community or nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to judge from the results of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2019-05-06/battle-indias-soul&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the election&lt;/a&gt;, the pluralist idea of India is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2018-11-23/triumph-hindu-majoritarianism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;receding into the past.&lt;/a&gt; At the polls, 44 percent of Hindus—a larger proportion than ever before—voted for the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), which seeks to transform India into a Hindu nation. According to public opinion surveys conducted between 2016 and 2018 by researchers at the Centre for the Study of Developing Societies and Azim Premji University, a majority of Hindus, including those who vote for other parties, now profess support for some of the BJP’s most important Hindu nationalist positions. This was also the first Indian election in which no major political party challenged the BJP’s position that India’s Hindu majority constitutes a single community that can rightfully claim ownership of the nation. Today, the basic struggle in Indian politics is not over whether Hindus and Hinduism should enjoy privileged status but over the precise legal and constitutional forms that privilege will take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2016-06-16/authoritarian-india&quot;&gt;Prime Minister Narendra Mod&lt;/a&gt;i has lost no time in trying to enshrine that status in law. Bills designed to further the BJP’s Hindu nationalist agenda—changes that once would have produced fierce debate—have already been enacted with the support of a wide spectrum of opposition parties. More such legislation is likely to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformation of India into a Hindu nation, however, was set in motion not by the BJP but by the other great force in Indian politics, the Congress party. That process began in 1969, with a nearly forgotten event in India’s political history: a major split in the Congress party that pushed the present-day Congress toward a Hindu majoritarian position and paved the way for the eventual success of BJP’s more extreme ideology five decades later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WHEN CONGRESS GOT RELIGION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful dissemination of an ideology by a political party requires an organization that links the leadership to the grassroots. The Congress party once had such an organization, forged under the leadership of Mohandas Gandhi during India’s nationalist movement, and inherited by India’s first Prime Minister, Jawaharlal Nehru. It was this organization that articulated and popularized the original pluralist idea of India in 1947.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nehru died in office in 1964, and, after two short-lived prime ministers, Indira Gandhi took power in 1966. She quickly found herself at odds with the party’s powerful regional bosses, known as the Syndicate, after she tried to wrest control over the party’s economic policy, political appointments, and choice of candidates to stand for elections. As a result of this conflict, Congress split into two blocs in 1969. The bloc led by Indira Gandhi evolved into the present-day Congress party, while the one controlled by the Syndicate disintegrated over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The split destroyed the organization that had linked the party leadership to the grassroots. It left Gandhi with two plausible routes to political survival: she could find a galvanizing popular issue in order to forge such links temporarily, or she could avoid elections altogether. She tried both. In the parliamentary election of 1971, the first after the split, she won by campaigning on a populist antipoverty platform. Then, in 1975, she postponed elections by declaring a national emergency. After the emergency ended, in 1977, voters punished her party with a resounding defeat in the next parliamentary poll. So, ahead of the next elections, Gandhi returned to the tactic of finding a galvanizing issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatefully, she found one in the politics of religion. At first, she tried to play all sides of the country’s religious divide. In the early 1980s, for example, she extended covert support to the militant Sikh preacher J. S. Bhindranwale, who called for an independent Sikh nation and who had been implicated in violence against Hindus in Punjab. By supporting Bhindranwale, Gandhi sought to weaken her main opposition in the populous state of Punjab, the Sikh-led Akali Dal party, as well as prop up her own power base at the expense of other regional leaders within the Punjab Congress. In 1984, she reversed herself and sent the Indian army into the Golden Temple, the holiest Sikh shrine, to root out Bhindranwale and his militant supporters, who had set up base there. Gandhi hoped that the siege, codenamed Operation Blue Star, would send Hindus a strong signal ahead of a parliamentary election that her government was capable of protecting them as well as safeguarding India’s territorial integrity. The army succeeded in ousting and killing Bhindrandwale, but the move antagonized many of India’s Sikhs who did not support Bhindranwale or his ideology but viewed the army’s entry into the Golden Temple as sacrilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandhi played for Hindu favor in Muslim-majority Kashmir, as well. In 1983, she aligned herself with the Hindu minority there during regional elections. But the Congress party lost, and a popular Muslim leader, Farooq Abdullah, was elected chief minister of Kashmir. A year later, Gandhi dismissed Abdullah and his elected government, to the fury of much of the state’s Muslim population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, such machinations would be Gandhi’s undoing. In October 1984, two of her Sikh bodyguards assassinated her in retribution for Operation Blue Star. Hindu mobs retaliated by attacking thousands of Sikhs. Congress was complicit in the anti-Sikh violence: some of the party’s leaders even participated in it. When Gandhi’s son Rajiv took over as prime minister, he excused the violence by saying, “When a big tree falls, the ground will shake.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Congress has given up on making an ideological case for secularism.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rajiv Gandhi followed in his mother’s footsteps by first trying to balance religious interests against one another and then moving decisively toward Hindu majoritarianism. In 1986, a Congress government allowed Hindus to worship at a disputed site in the north Indian town of Ayodhya that was home to a mosque. This gave a boost to Hindu revivalist organizations, which had launched a popular movement claiming that the mosque had been built on the birthplace of the Hindu deity Ram and demanding that it be replaced by a temple. In 1988, Congress asked Arun Govil, an actor who played Ram in a wildly successful television show, to campaign for the party’s candidate in a by-election. Govil, dressed in saffron robes, asked voters to “take the name of Lord Ram and vote for the Congress.” In the 1989 general election, Gandhi launched Congress’ campaign from Ayodhya, promising to establish &lt;em&gt;Ram rajya&lt;/em&gt;—literally, “the rule of Lord Ram”—if he won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandhi was assassinated in 1991. In 1992, the national government led by the Congress party failed to protect the Ayodhya mosque from a Hindu mob that destroyed it—and with it, Congress’ secularist credentials. Since then, Congress has given up on making an ideological case for secularism. Instead, influential Congress leaders have argued that the party should be careful not to advocate too strongly for the rights of India’s religious minorities—in particular Muslims—lest it be perceived as anti-Hindu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2019 election campaign, in which Congress sought to regain power after five years of BJP rule, Congress dropped the word “secularism” from its manifesto altogether. The party’s then president, Rahul Gandhi (son of Rajiv and grandson of Indira), also pointedly avoided the term on the campaign trail. Instead, both Rahul and his sister and principal co-campaigner, Priyanka Gandhi, signaled their alignment with India’s Hindu majority by conspicuously visiting Hindu temples and avoiding mosques and other non-Hindu places of worship. Both were silent on the question of minority rights, including a spate of lynchings of Muslims under the BJP government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LEARNING FROM THE MASTERS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress’s sustained move toward Hindu majoritarianism over several decades created fertile ground for the more extreme ideology of the BJP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP, which was formally founded in 1980, traces its lineage to the Bharatiya Jana Sangh (BJS). The BJS was founded in 1951 as the political wing of the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh (RSS), a cadre-based organization devoted to the cause of establishing a Hindu nation. For decades, the BJS was the main advocate of Hindu nationalism in the electoral arena. Worn down by a lack of success, the BJS substantially moderated its platform and, in 1977, merged with the ideologically diverse Janata Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1980, BJS members left the Janata Party to form the BJP. They initially conceived of the BJP not as a Hindu nationalist party but as a centrist one. They had given up on Hindu nationalism after years of failure, having come to believe that it would never attract a popular following in India. Indeed, in the 1984 elections, Congress was the most pro-Hindu of all the major parties, and the BJP, as the political scientist James Manor noted, was “in the curious position of being more tolerant of minorities than Congress was.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress won a large majority in 1984. In response, the BJP rapidly and gladly returned to its roots, having witnessed the popular legitimacy that Congress had managed to create for Hindu majoritarian politics. The BJP’s 1989 manifesto restored the emphasis on Hindu nationalism that had been missing from its 1984 platform. It also included a statement in support of building a Ram temple at Ayodhya, an issue on which it had been silent in 1984.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP was soon able to outflank Congress as the champion of India’s Hindus thanks to the one thing that Congress did not have after 1969: a strong grassroots organization. It also benefits from the formidable organizational networks of the RSS and its affiliates. Indeed, several BJP officials are considered to be “on deputation” from the RSS. The BJP has never undergone a nationwide split despite major disagreements among its senior leaders. In recent years, the BJP has also substantially extended and strengthened the links between the leadership and the grassroots by expanding party membership, pioneering the use of social media, and appointing thousands of new local functionaries to help connect the party to its target voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Congress’s gradual move toward Hindu majoritarianism created fertile ground for the more extreme ideology of the BJP.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this has meant that the BJP could formulate and disseminate the idea of India as a Hindu nation—and market Modi as its chief advocate—with an effectiveness that Congress has not demonstrated for decades. In traveling across India during this year’s election campaign, I found that the BJP’s ideological message, in contrast to that of the Congress, was clear and consistent from top to bottom: the regional leader, the election candidate, and the party worker at the polling booth level said exactly the same things that Modi did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BJP’s organization also helped it further its ideological agenda by forging alliances with other parties: strong support from the rank and file allowed it to make concessions even to its former opponents. Congress, in contrast, was not able to strike deals with even ideologically proximate parties for fear of opposition from its party workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MODI’S MOVES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During Modi’s first term in office, most of the steps the government took in the direction of Hindu nationalism took place outside the legislative arena. The BJP appointed a Hindu religious leader as chief minister of India’s largest state, changed history textbooks to identify Hindus as the country’s original inhabitants, renamed cities and roads after places and figures from Hindu mythology (replacing Muslim ones), tacitly sanctioned efforts to convert Muslims to Hinduism (which the party called “homecoming”), and supported and even incited vigilante violence against Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it did not have the mandate to introduce new legislation. The two bills associated with a Hindu nationalist ideology that it tried to pass lapsed for want of support in Parliament. The first of these criminalized the system of instant divorce among Muslims. The BJP cast this bill as an effort to protect women’s rights. But it was also aimed at eroding the autonomy of Muslims in matters of civil law. For Hindu nationalists, who have long criticized the protections afforded to Muslims (the largest religious minority in India) as instances of special treatment, downgrading these protections is as important as upgrading the status of Hindus. The second introduced religion-based preferences in India’s citizenship policies for the first time by relaxing eligibility requirements for non-Muslim migrants from some of India’s neighboring countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even today BJP does not have the numbers to pass such legislation on its own: it holds a majority of seats in the lower house of Parliament but falls short of a majority in the upper house, even after taking into account the seats won by its alliance members. Yet it has won support for its ideological agenda among parties outside its governing alliance. Some of these parties are jumping on the BJP’s bandwagon based on a calculation that the electorate is now more receptive to Hindu nationalism than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first bill that the new government introduced in Parliament revived the criminalization of instant divorce among Muslims. Some of the BJP’s allies opposed the bill, but they did not vote against it, and the BJP was able to win the support of some parties outside its alliance. The bill passed in both houses and was enacted into law in July this year. Days later, the BJP enacted an amendment in India’s antiterrorist legislation that allows the government to designate individuals as terrorists regardless of their organizational affiliation with a relatively low burden of proof. This law not only supports the Hindu nationalist vision of a muscular security state but also empowers the government to pursue its ideological enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following month, the government issued a notification &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2019-08-08/modi-crosses-rubicon-kashmir&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;curtailing the autonomy&lt;/a&gt; constitutionally guaranteed to Kashmir, India’s only Muslim-majority state. Ending this autonomy is one of the oldest and most controversial tenets of its Hindu nationalist agenda. It also succeeded in getting both houses of Parliament to approve a bill that stripped Kashmir of its status as a state within the Indian federal union altogether. Remarkably, a number of regional parties within and outside the BJP alliance, who could reasonably have been expected to oppose attempts to curtain regional autonomy, supported the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress has in the meantime been engulfed in a fresh organizational crisis. Rahul Gandhi resigned as the party’s president immediately after its poor performance in the elections. After months without leadership, the party appointed Sonia Gandhi as its interim president. The party seems confused about how to respond to the BJP’s moves. Although Congress party leaders in Parliament opposed the BJP-sponsored legislation, some members not in Parliament tweeted in support of it. The gap between leaders and the grassroots, meanwhile, has widened. As a result, just when the vision of a secular, pluralistic India is threatened as never before, the Congress party—the original incubator of that vision—is at its weakest. And, to some degree, it has itself to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;KANCHAN CHANDRA is Professor of Politics at New York University.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, September 11, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Kanchan Chandra</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/india/2019-09-11/roots-hindu-nationalisms-triumph-india</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/11/rtx6uw4s.jpg?itok=A96qKm6l</image>
 <media:description>A supporter of the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) waves the party flag during a rally in New Delhi, India, in May 2019 - REUTERS / Adnan Abidi</media:description>
 <subtitle>What the BJP Learned From the Congress Party</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-11T13:44:20-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Bolton Was Trump’s Best Match, Until He Wasn’t</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-11/bolton-was-trumps-best-match-until-he-wasnt</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;In less than three years, U.S. President Donald Trump has had three wildly different national security advisers: a campaign aide with a checkered past, a respected general, and an ideologue with strong views apparently consonant with his own. All ultimately failed. John Bolton’s firing is just the latest and most dramatic episode in Trump’s national security travails. Though the outgoing adviser drove tough policies on Iran and other issues, his peremptory, no-compromise style proved, over time, unacceptable to the president, who “disagreed strongly with many of his suggestions.” His firing underscores the difficulty in filling this particular role, whether with an honest broker or a straightforward adviser, for a president who disdains process and tends to follow his “gut.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job of national security adviser is a presidential creation, neither established in legislation nor requiring Senate confirmation. Ideally, the adviser connects the president to other senior officials, assures that he hears all relevant viewpoints, and sees that his policy decisions are translated into action. In practice, the ability of advisers to function effectively depends less on the process they establish than on the proclivities and preferences of the president they serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few presidents had thought less about the management of national security policy the day they entered the White House than Donald J. Trump. He had run for president without really expecting to win and focused little on the details of governing even after he did. In the White House, Trump has eschewed formal process and expertise and instead relied on his often changing impulses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of Trump’s three national security advisers has tried, with mixed success, to tailor to the president’s instincts a process that brings government expertise to bear on decision-making. Bolton was perhaps substantively and temperamentally the most suited to help Trump pursue his “America first” foreign policy. But even he found himself on the outs with this decidedly mercurial president. And Bolton’s core style—rushing to decisions, excluding advisers with dissenting views—may have brought short-run results, but over time it was a recipe for policy disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A TEXTBOOK PROCESS REBUFFED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s original choice for national security adviser, retired Lieutenant General Michael Flynn, had been his campaign’s most senior adviser on national security policy. Flynn was an odd choice. He had extreme views on the threat of Islamic terrorism, questionable relationships with foreign entities and governments, and a rosy view of Russia. He had also been fired from his last government job for managerial incompetence. But Trump valued loyalty, and he ignored the entreaties of both President Barack Obama and Chris Christie, the original chair of his transition team, who warned the incoming president against appointing Flynn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flynn was in over his head from the outset. He was supposed to establish himself as the single center of power on national security affairs in the White House. But instead he competed for access, attention, and control with figures such as Steve Bannon, the president’s chief strategist, who secured a seat on the main Principals Committee of the National Security Council (NSC), and Jared Kushner, the president’s son-in-law, who served as the main conduit between Trump and certain foreign governments. Before Flynn could do much more than hire a few people who shared his dark view of the world, he was embroiled in controversy centering on his contacts with the Russian ambassador after the election. Ousted just 24 days into the job, Flynn set a record for the shortest tenure of anyone serving in the position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flynn was one of few national security figures Trump knew personally, and when it came time to replace him, Trump had to improvise. For other such appointments, he had opted for people who looked the part—either strong generals such as James Mattis and John Kelly, whom he appointed as secretaries of the Departments of Defense and Homeland Security, or successful corporate executives such as Rex Tillerson, the ExxonMobil CEO who became Trump’s first secretary of state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Trump found another broad-shouldered army officer, Lieutenant General H. R. McMaster, to take the national security adviser job. McMaster had a storied career as a combat veteran in Iraq and Afghanistan. He was also a well-respected defense intellectual, having helped draft the army’s counterinsurgency strategy in Iraq and written a stinging critique of military leadership during the Vietnam War. McMaster’s appointment was widely welcomed in Washington’s corridors of power. Arizona Senator John McCain, long a leading Trump critic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2017/feb/20/trump-appoints-hr-mcmaster-national-security-adviser&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; approvingly that he “could not imagine a better, more capable national security team than the one we have right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;H. R. McMaster’s was a textbook NSC process.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he had never before served in Washington, McMaster approached the job with textbook precision. He met with all of his living predecessors and asked for their advice. He weeded out some of the more ideological staffers Flynn had brought in and reassured the many diplomatic, military, and intelligence officials detailed from other agencies that he respected their service and work, even if they hadn’t been part of the Trump campaign. He reinstated the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the intelligence director to the NSC’s Principals Committee (Flynn had removed them) and brought homeland security back under the NSC’s auspices (Flynn had separated it). He moved Bannon off the NSC committee. And he established routine meetings at multiple levels for the purposes of both long-term planning and crisis response. McMaster’s was a textbook NSC process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Trump had no interest in detailed policy briefings or long meetings devoted to considering all available options. The president believed in his gut over advice and process: “My gut tells me more sometimes than anybody else’s brain can ever tell me,” Trump once &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-slams-fed-chair-questions-climate-change-and-threatens-to-cancel-putin-meeting-in-wide-ranging-interview-with-the-post/2018/11/27/4362fae8-f26c-11e8-aeea-b85fd44449f5_story.html?utm_term=.a83ece308ee2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;declared&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McMaster never caught on. He would brief the president with formal, elaborate presentations. He called meetings to go over every detail of policy. But he never established the sort of close, informal relationship with the president that was essential for success. Other players soon understood that Trump was ignoring McMaster’s process—and so they began to ignore it as well. Mattis and Tillerson met frequently to decide what to do, leaving McMaster out of their deliberations. And they would often ignore his directives or send lower-level people to the meetings he called. McMaster soldiered on. But in the end, he was no doubt relieved when Trump told him in March 2018 that it was time for him to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A BRASH ADVISER ON A LEASH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Bolton, a national security player with long experience and strong views, many of which were more aligned with Trump’s “America first” perspective than McMaster’s had been. Bolton understood that Trump didn’t want structured meetings and detailed briefings. He set out to streamline the NSC staff by eliminating positions dealing with such issues as cybersecurity and global pandemics. He reduced the frequency of interagency meetings. And he focused on supporting the president by giving him his best advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the president, Bolton preferred to work alone, behind closed doors, and he communicated with staff mainly by e-mail rather than face-to-face. He favored one-on-one meetings with other principals over the larger advisory meetings that characterized the NSC in previous administrations. The new tone was set within weeks of his coming to the White House, when Bolton decided not to convene a single meeting of the NSC principals prior to Trump’s historic Singapore Summit meeting with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un in June 2018 or before the president met with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Helsinki the next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Bolton enjoyed a lot of leeway to get things done, but sometimes his views ran afoul of Trump’s instincts.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By acting outside of formal processes, Bolton, who was 70 years old, could seize what was probably his last opportunity to change policy to his liking. He had long seen arms control, international agreements, the United Nations, and other multilateral institutions as unacceptable constraints on U.S. power and sovereignty. Now he moved quickly to withdraw the United States from the Iran nuclear deal and the Reagan-era treaty eliminating intermediate-range nuclear forces. He was the force behind Trump’s speech to the UN General Assembly last fall, which was a broad indictment of multilateralism and defense of sovereignty. He put his stamp on hard-line policies with respect to Iran, North Korea, and Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as he was pushing in a direction that Trump supported, or for policies that didn’t engage him, Bolton enjoyed a lot of leeway to get things done. But sometimes his views ran afoul of Trump’s instincts—notably, the president’s conviction that he could negotiate great deals with everyone and his fear of getting dragged into a new war.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump made clear, for example, that he disagreed with Bolton’s uncompromising line on North Korea—so much so that he left Bolton out of the last-minute meeting with Kim Jong Un at the demilitarized zone earlier this year and openly contradicted his assessment of the North’s missile threat. Bolton was also initially left off the invitation list for a meeting with Trump and his top advisers on Afghanistan, in that case because he opposed withdrawing U.S. forces from the country. Trump likewise reversed Bolton’s push (supported by many other top advisers) to retaliate when Iran downed a U.S. drone. “He wants to start 3 wars a day,” Trump once &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/trump-john-bolton-doctrine-iran-venezuela-war-427ca897-aaa1-4e10-a7c9-2a67c1d20354.html?utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=newsletter_axiossneakpeek&amp;amp;stream=top&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;complained&lt;/a&gt; of Bolton, “but I have him on a leash.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those concerned about Bolton’s inclinations, such restraint was reassuring—to a degree. “I am the national security adviser,” Bolton has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/02/04/john-bolton-living-his-dream-224546&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;admitted&lt;/a&gt;. “I am not the national decision-maker.” But there was only so much comfort to be found in a willful president constraining a willful national security adviser. For Bolton was the polar opposite of the model for the job established by Brent Scowcroft, national security adviser to President George H. W. Bush, and followed in the main by Scowcroft’s successors. Bolton was an ideologue who thought he knew the answers, excluded those who disagreed, and destroyed relationships and institutions that took his predecessors decades to build. To the extent his tenure served the president, it came at great cost to the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later, most presidents settle on a national security adviser who meets their personal and operational needs. Sometimes that choice is good for the republic, sometimes not. For the office is a two-edged sword. In a harmonious administration, the occupant both serves the president and runs a policy process that engages senior officials and prepares issues for presidential decision. But in a fractious administration, the adviser can use that closeness to the president to drive rash actions that reflect the idiosyncratic predilections of the adviser, the president, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Presidents get the national security process they deserve,” Stephen Hadley, President George W. Bush’s national security adviser, once rightly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/security/reports/2017/01/05/295673/process-makes-perfect/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;observed&lt;/a&gt;. But the nation deserves better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;IVO H. DAALDER is President of the Chicago Council on Global Affairs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. M. DESTLER is Saul I. Stern Professor of Civic Engagement at the University of Maryland School of Public Policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are the co-authors of &lt;em&gt;In the Shadow of the Oval Office: Profiles of the National Security Advisers and the Presidents They Served—From JFK to George W. Bush&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, September 11, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Ivo H. Daalder and I. M. Destler</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-11/bolton-was-trumps-best-match-until-he-wasnt</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/11/h_15261568.jpg?itok=Xz1U7vdT</image>
 <media:description>Trump and Bolton in the Oval Office, August 2019 - Doug Mills  / The New York Times / Redux</media:description>
 <subtitle>For a Mercurial President, National Security Adviser Is the Hardest Spot to Fill</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T10:49:00-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A Post-Soviet “War and Peace”</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/russian-federation/2019-09-10/post-soviet-war-and-peace</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 23, 2014, Russian President Vladimir Putin attended the final day of the Winter Olympics in Sochi, the most expensive winter games to date and the first hosted by an Eastern-bloc country since the Soviet Union’s collapse. Amid the fanfare and the flag-waving, the Russian leader’s attention was likely elsewhere—across the Black Sea, on the Crimean peninsula. Just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-ukraine-putin-crimea-decision/26889839.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hours before&lt;/a&gt; the start of the closing ceremony, Putin had decided to invade the Ukrainian territory. One can almost picture him in the early hours after dawn, eyes fixed on a map of Crimea—a world-historical actor deciding precisely how to shape the course of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tableau invites comparison with a scene from &lt;em&gt;War and Peace.&lt;/em&gt; In&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;his celebrated epic about Russia during the Napoleonic Wars, Leo Tolstoy portrays Bonaparte on a hill, looking down at Moscow. The &lt;em&gt;empereur des Français &lt;/em&gt;envisions rebuilding the Russian capital as a western European city—replacing its onion domes with Enlightenment temples and refashioning its Slavic culture after his own. In the early decades of the nineteenth century, Napoleon (like Putin after him) wanted to construct his own international order. To that end, he crossed into Russian territory uninvited, beginning a bloody and unnecessary war that ended with Russian troops in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/russian-federation/2014-04-17/russias-latest-land-grab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;annexation of Crimea&lt;/a&gt; hardly measures up. And yet contained in the pages of Tolstoy’s nineteenth-century novel is a premonition of Russia’s current, conflicted relationship with the West. One hundred and fifty years after publication, &lt;em&gt;War and Peace&lt;/em&gt; still sheds light on the tensions that structure Moscow’s relations with other great powers and in particular with the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RUSSIANS APART&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tolstoy opens his novel in 1805. The Russia he describes is calm and self-confident, sure of itself as a military power and still untempted by the revolutionary excitement that had recently boiled over in France. But the Russia of 1805 is also riven by inequality. If the peasants and aristocrats in Tsar Alexander I’s vast empire are all in some sense Russian, they are Russians apart. To make this point, Tolstoy writes the first 40 or so pages of &lt;em&gt;War and Peace&lt;/em&gt; in French. This section depicts two of the novel’s heroes, Pierre Bezukhov and Prince Andrey, in a St. Petersburg salon. The characters speak French and identify with Napoleon. For Pierre, the French leader is an example of European liberty, a role model for Russians living amid tsarist despotism and sloth. For Prince Andrey, Napoleon is military excellence personified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the novel, Tolstoy develops the contrast between Westernized Russians and their unpretentious, emphatically non-Western counterparts. Tolstoy’s central character, Natasha Rostova, is another of the novel’s European-oriented aristocrats. But she is also something else. In a famous scene, Rostova spontaneously dances to a Russian folk tune while visiting a relative who lives among peasants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here was a young countess, educated by a French émigré governess—where, when and how had she imbibed the spirit of that peasant dance along with the Russian air she breathed, and those movements which the &lt;em&gt;pas de châle&lt;/em&gt; ought to have squeezed out of her long ago? But her movements and the spirit of them were truly Russian, inimitable, unteachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tolstoy embeds Natasha’s story within a three-part tale of national awakening. Her betrayal by a handsome, Europeanized lover reflects the seductions of French culture. Her suffering anticipates the burning of Moscow by Napoleon. And her recovery and return home resemble Russia’s victory over France in 1812.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre traces a similar journey. He evinces a deep admiration for Napoleon in 1805, but after experiencing war, Pierre changes his viewpoint. He wanders the Borodino battlefield, shedding his infatuation with the West and with the French Revolution. He befriends a Russian peasant, Platon Karataev, who gives him a robust education in Russian folkways. While the French occupy Moscow, the new Pierre sets out to kill Napoleon—so closely aligned has he become with the defense of Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare the events of the nineteenth century with those of the twenty-first is in many ways absurd. No latter-day Napoleon descended on Moscow in 2014. In fact, it was Russia that invaded eastern Ukraine and swallowed up Crimea. And yet the world Tolstoy describes has a number of clear parallels with the present. Although Putin’s Russia harbors no aristocracy and no peasantry, it is once again a highly unequal society. And just as in tsarist Russia, the country’s elite devoted itself to imitating the West after the Soviet Union fell—learning English this time, rather than French; taking up Western ideas, especially with regard to economics; and assimilating American or western European styles of music, cuisine, dress, and education. In the twenty-first century, travel and study in the West are the marks of a wellborn Russian, just as they were for Tolstoy’s fictional creations Pierre and Prince Andrey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the similarities are palpable in times of peace, they are even clearer in times of war. Renewed tension with Europe and the United States has enabled Putin to turn away from the West, both politically and culturally. Just as once, Russia would dance the &lt;em&gt;pas de châle &lt;/em&gt;no longer, now it would submit no longer to the liberal international order. Among the most important consequences of the Ukraine crisis has been the widening desire, in the Kremlin and in Russia at large, not just to deviate from the Western model but to supplant it with a Russian model. Nobody who had read &lt;em&gt;War and Peace&lt;/em&gt; prior to 2014 should have been surprised by this turn of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time since Napoleon’s day that conflict with the West brought Russia itself into focus. After the German invasion of the Soviet Union in the middle of World War II, the Soviet leader Joseph Stalin revived the Russian Orthodox Church. He later proclaimed the Russian people as the true heroes of the war, a status to which Russians remain attached, both at home and in the diaspora. Stalin’s efforts did much to promote an idea of authenticity and Russianness—over and against the internationalist rhetoric of socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Soviet Union had a Soviet rather than a Westernized elite. And during the Soviet years, inequality was not the central issue of the day. In these and other respects, Putin governs a Russia that comes closer to the Westernizing tsarist autocracy of 1805 than to Stalin’s Soviet Union. The comparison can help explain what happened after 2014—when Russia again found itself in opposition to the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States and Europe responded to Russia’s annexation of Crimea by imposing sanctions on Moscow and attempting to isolate Russia internationally. Such measures may have deterred Russia from extending its military reach within Ukraine; they were a valid response to the crisis. But they also reinforced binary thinking in Russia. Putin invented a boogeyman West—and the West furnished some of the raw material for his caricature. An us-versus-them frame is the price the United States and Europe have paid for economic sanctions, which have so far elicited more defiance than submission from Russians. Russian countersanctions on European goods, for example, have fueled a revival of Russian cuisine and local foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Russians see themselves as inhabitants of an embattled civilization. The United States has reinforced that view by attempting to isolate the country internationally. In practice, the isolation has consisted of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2019/08/22/why-russias-relationship-with-g-collapsed/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;expelling Russia from the G-8 in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, minimizing high-level diplomatic meetings, and refusing to invite the Russian president to certain symbolic events, such as World War II commemorations. But efforts to sequester the country have backfired, insofar as they appear to stigmatize not only Putin’s government but all of Russia. The more Russia sees itself confronted with a binary choice—authenticity or Western rejection—the more an escalatory conflict acquires the aura of a self-fulfilling prophecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BEYOND BINARIES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, then, are the lessons from Tolstoy’s time that can be applied to the present? In &lt;em&gt;War and Peace,&lt;/em&gt; Tolstoy reflects on the wages of imitation and dissects Russia’s geopolitical culture, including its penchant for conflict with the West. This is a story that plays out again and again. Putin’s anti-Western foreign policy goes back at least to 2007, when the Russian president surprised the Munich Security Conference with his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/11/world/europe/11munich.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fiery condemnation&lt;/a&gt; of U.S. hegemony. Putin wanted to mark the arrival of a post-Soviet Russia at the Sochi Olympics in 2014. He achieved his goal—not through the games but rather through the Ukraine crisis, which forced Russia’s Western-leaning elites into internal or actual exile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western governments risk fueling the binary thinking that undergirds Putin’s rule—for example, by cheerleading civil society as the alternative to Putin’s regime, thus confusing internal Russian politics with outside Western interests. A more astute cultural diplomacy would subvert binaries by emphasizing the countless links between Russia and the West in music, dance, art, religion, architecture, cinema, and, of course, literature. Tolstoy, one might note, drew on the work of Henry David Thoreau in formulating his thoughts on pacifism and civil disobedience; in turn, Tolstoy’s novels indirectly influenced Martin Luther King’s doctrine of nonviolence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Natashas, Pierres, and Prince Andreys of today should not be forced to choose between a life led in English and the defense of the motherland. A viable Western approach to Russia is one that tries not to subdue or subsume Moscow but to promote Russia as a country at ease with itself and with the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;MICHAEL KIMMAGE is Professor of History at the Catholic University of America. His next book, &lt;em&gt;The Abandonment of the West: The History of an Idea in American Foreign Policy,&lt;/em&gt; is forthcoming with Basic Books in April 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, September 10, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Michael Kimmage</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/russian-federation/2019-09-10/post-soviet-war-and-peace</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/09/h_11.00871621_0.jpg?itok=WAZp1e_R</image>
 <media:description>A general view of the Peterhof Palace near St. Petersburg, Russia in October 2012 - Xinhua / eyevine / Redux</media:description>
 <subtitle>What Tolstoy’s Masterwork Explains About Putin’s Foreign Policy</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T17:56:21-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Self-Inflicted Recession</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-10/self-inflicted-recession</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is in its 11th year of uninterrupted economic expansion, unemployment has hit a historic low, and growth, while decelerating, still hums along. Yet anxiety about the next recession seems to mount with each new tariff or tweet that President Donald Trump lobs at China as part of his trade war—and for good reason. The president’s policies are clearly hurting tradeable sectors of the U.S. economy, especially manufacturing, which must contend with the double whammy of U.S. tariffs on imported inputs and Chinese tariffs on exports of finished goods. U.S. producers of vehicles, electronics, and agricultural goods, among other things, are all scrambling to disentangle their supply chains from China. But doing so is costly and complicated, and many of them are suffering as a result.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade war may not be enough to tip an otherwise healthy U.S. economy into recession. But if it does, the United States will be in a uniquely bad position to fight its way out again. The country is almost certain to enter the next downturn with historically high levels of public debt. That is worrying because governments in this position have historically failed to apply enough fiscal stimulus—that is, boost the economy through increased government spending as well as indirect measures like tax cuts—to counteract recessions. At the same time, short-term U.S. interest rates are already relatively low, meaning there will be limited room to cut them—the other main tool that governments have to battle downturns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both problems—the trade war and the lack of preparedness to offset its potential downsides—share an important commonality: they are self-inflicted wounds, own-goals resulting from fateful policy mistakes that have been at best unchecked and at worst supported by a majority in the U.S. Congress. By definition, all recessions are market failures. But the next one may be a government failure as well. And a government that causes a recession is probably not a government that should be trusted to lead a recovery. Arsonists make lousy fire chiefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OWN-GOAL ECONOMICS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the gathering recessionary angst—recent Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all_2008&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;gprop=news&amp;amp;q=recession&quot;&gt;trends&lt;/a&gt; show searches for “recession” approaching the heights of the last downturn—the U.S. economy is still on relatively solid ground, at least for the time being. Unemployment is low, real wages are rising, and while job growth has slowed it is still strong enough to fuel robust consumer spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the trade war has taken a toll on manufacturing, which has contracted by two percent this year. Since the beginning of 2019, the sector added just 44,000 jobs, compared to 170,000 over the same period last year. The overall impact on the economy has been limited, because manufacturing now accounts for a much smaller share of the U.S. economy than it did in the past (11 percent today compared to 27 percent in 1950). But the effects of the trade war can be felt beyond the manufacturing sector. With so much policy uncertainty, a wide range of American businesses are delaying or deferring investment. According to the most recent GDP &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bea.gov/system/files/2019-08/gdp2q19_2nd_0.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the Commerce Department, business investment fell by 0.6 percent in the second quarter of this year. That is a relatively small decline in a historically volatile measure, but it is consistent with business surveys that show trade policy uncertainty deterring investment.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;In an increasingly interconnected global economy, trouble in any of the world’s major economies is likely to be felt in the United States. &amp;#13;
&amp;#13;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade war could shave as much as a full percentage point off of U.S. GDP growth by early 2020, according to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/notes/feds-notes/does-trade-policy-uncertainty-affect-global-economic-activity-20190904.htm&quot;&gt;estimate&lt;/a&gt; by Federal Reserve economists. In recent quarters, growth has averaged around two percent, meaning that the trade war could end up cutting the U.S. growth rate in half. One percent growth isn’t a recession, which is typically defined as two consecutive quarters of declining growth. But it is slow enough that unemployment will start to rise, and if some other economic shock occurs—a bursting credit bubble, a lasting government shutdown, a much larger than expected escalation of the trade war—the economy could tip into recession.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also global repercussions to consider. Germany, Europe’s largest economy and among the continent’s most export-oriented, may already be in recession—in part because of Trump’s trade war and in part because the German government, as is its wont, has eschewed the countercyclical spending that the economy needs. South Korea, Japan, and China, all of which are more trade-dependent than the United States, are experiencing slower growth. And because the U.S. economy is linked to all of these countries, not just through trade but through financial markets, there is a risk of a negative feedback loop. In an increasingly interconnected global economy, trouble in any of the world’s major economies is likely to be felt in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;KEYNESIANISM INVERTED&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the trade war or some other negative development sets off the next recession, the United States is clearly unprepared to mount a commensurate fiscal and monetary response. On the fiscal side, the problem is not an economic one; it’s a political one. Among the most reckless decisions of the Trump administration was to push through a huge, regressive, deficit-financed tax cut. In addition to deepening inequality, the tax cuts will deprive the U.S. Treasury of $1.9 trillion in revenue over the next ten years, thereby pushing up national debt levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the United States is likely to enter the next recession with a debt-to-GDP ratio that is more than twice its historical average (around 80 compared to 35 percent). With debt and deficit levels already at historic highs, Washington might feel that it has limited ability to counter a recession through stimulus. That has indeed been the historical &lt;a href=&quot;https://eml.berkeley.edu/~dromer/papers/Romer&amp;amp;RomerCrisesandPolicyRevised.pdf&quot;&gt;pattern&lt;/a&gt;: governments that enter downturns with high debt levels implement fewer Keynesian-style countercyclical policies than governments with low debt levels. The result is that many more people end up suffering job and income losses than when robust fiscal responses are enacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the cruel irony is that austerity often delivers all pain and no gain, failing to bring debt and deficit levels down. Too little stimulus during a recession will mean slower growth and a deeper and longer recession, all of which &lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.repec.org/p/nbr/nberwo/23789.html&quot; title=&quot;柀嫰翿&quot;&gt;risks&lt;/a&gt; increasing debt levels. On the contrary, even with relatively high debt levels, stimulus spending helps to restore growth, which in turn boosts government revenues and makes debt and deficit reduction possible. (This is especially true when a government’s borrowing costs are low.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Especially if the next downturn is deep and lasting, waiting for the administration and Congress to act will likely impose severe burdens on economically vulnerable people and delay the beginning of a recovery. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to know for sure whether this or any future U.S. administration would choose austerity over stimulus when the latter is clearly needed, but the recent track record is concerning. Even with a (slightly) more functional government under President Barack Obama, the U.S. pivoted from stimulus spending to deficit reduction well before the private sector was ready to grow on its own. The result was a recovery from the 2007–08 financial crisis that was initially quite weak. Given the rabid partisanship and deepening gridlock that has taken hold since that time, the risk of an inadequate fiscal response has only grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of political will extends beyond standard stimulus or bailout packages. In the last recession, the U.S. government offered workers extended unemployment compensation, enhanced nutritional support, and subsidized employment programs. It also offered fiscal relief to state governments, a vital measure for those that are legally required to balance their budgets. None of these responses will automatically kick in when the next recession arrives. On the contrary, they are considered discretionary programs, meaning that Congress must affirmatively vote for them and allocate their funds. Especially if the next downturn is deep and lasting, waiting for the administration and Congress to act will likely impose severe burdens on economically vulnerable people and delay the beginning of a recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NOTHING TO CUT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central banks face a different set of constraints. Unlike some of the governments they serve, the central banks in advanced economies remain for the most part highly functional and politically independent. Although Trump has waged a vicious campaign against Federal Reserve chair Jerome Powell, the institution, to its credit, appears to have largely blocked him out. But that doesn’t change the fact that the Fed’s main weapon against recession—the federal funds rate, currently between 2 and 2.25 percent and trending downward—could well be too low when the next downturn hits for rate cuts to make much of a difference, especially if the next downturn is relatively deep. In the past, the Fed has cut short-term interest rates by five to six percentage points during recessions. For the next one, it will very likely have less than half that space to maneuver. (The Fed has shown a historical distaste for negative interest rates.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, in the last crisis, central bankers did more than slash short-term interest rates; they used large-scale bond purchases, or quantitative easing, to reduce longer-term interest rates not under their direct control. But at the end of the day, all of their efforts are designed to lower the price of credit. And as the recent history of advanced economies makes clear, very low rates—even negative ones—can be insufficient to get flagging economies moving again. In addition to the credit-creating effect of monetary policy, economies in recession need the demand-inducing effect of fiscal policy. By themselves, neither fiscal policy nor monetary policy is adequate. Together, they constitute a potent anti-recessionary one-two punch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next recession, however, the United States risks being able to rely on neither. The Trump administration is whipping up economic headwinds with its trade war while its tax policies squander resources that would be more productively deployed in the next downturn. And with interest rates already low, the Fed will have limited ability to reignite growth. The United States has recovered from previous downturns through bipartisan political planning, cooperation, and policy solutions that were up to the task. This time, the country will be stuck with own-goal economics, and the prognosis isn’t good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;JARED BERNSTEIN is a Senior Fellow at the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities and former Chief Economist to Vice President Joseph Biden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, September 10, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Jared Bernstein</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-10/self-inflicted-recession</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/09/wallst.jpg?itok=jKYmPal4</image>
 <media:description>The New York Stock Exchange building in New York, May 2010 - Lucas Jackson / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>The Next Downturn Will Be Political—and Tough to Escape</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T09:01:36-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Great-Power Competition Is Washington’s Top Priority—but Not the Public’s</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-09/great-power-competition-washingtons-top-priority-not-publics</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;For all the acrimony in Washington today, the city’s foreign policy establishment is settling on a rare bipartisan consensus: that the world has entered a new era of great-power competition. The struggle between the United States and other great powers, the emerging consensus holds, will fundamentally shape geopolitics going forward, for good or ill. And more than terrorism, climate change, or nuclear weapons in Iran or North Korea, the threats posed by these other great powers—namely, China and Russia—will consume U.S. foreign-policy makers in the decades ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s administration has been a prime mover in setting this new agenda. Its National Security Strategy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/NSS-Final-12-18-2017-0905.pdf&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in December 2017, portrayed China and Russia as seeking “to shape a world antithetical to U.S. values and interests,” with Beijing displacing the United States in the Indo-Pacific and Russia establishing spheres of influence near its borders. When he presented the new National Defense Strategy in January 2018, then Secretary of Defense James Mattis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Transcripts/Transcript/Article/1420042/remarks-by-secretary-mattis-on-the-national-defense-strategy/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that “Great Power competition—not terrorism—is now the primary focus of U.S. national security.” Secretary of State Mike Pompeo said much the same in April, when he told NATO foreign ministers that the world had entered “a new era of great-power competition,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/26/world/asia/united-states-china-conflict.html&quot;&gt;adding&lt;/a&gt; separately that “China wants to be the dominant economic and military power of the world, spreading its authoritarian vision for society and its corrupt practices worldwide.” GPC has become the Pentagon’s newest acronym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the consensus extends well beyond the current administration, to foreign policy experts, current and former national security officials—and much of the Democratic presidential primary field. Massachusetts Senator Elizabeth Warren &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/what-elizabeth-warrens-foreign-policy-speech-means/576928/&quot;&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; last year that both Russia and China “are working flat out to remake the global order to suit their own priorities,” while Vermont Senator Bernie Sanders decried the rise of a new authoritarian axis that includes Moscow and Beijing and has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/berniesanders/posts/2118505764871083?comment_id=2118564068198586&amp;amp;reply_comment_id=2118580954863564&amp;amp;comment_tracking=%7B%22tn%22%3A%22R%22%7D&quot;&gt;ignited&lt;/a&gt; “a global struggle of enormous consequence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a striking disconnect, however, between the consensus in Washington and the views of most Americans. Survey after survey shows that while concerns about China are gradually rising, the vast majority of Americans are relatively unconcerned with great-power competition and much more focused on other threats. That could pose a problem for the United States’ new competitive strategy. A generation-long great-power competition demands national-level focus and new economic and military approaches, all of which will be difficult to achieve without popular support.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MIND THE GAP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the hardening consensus among foreign policy elites, it is remarkable that the American public expresses far different sentiments. In a survey &lt;a href=&quot;https://engage.thechicagocouncil.org/rejecting-retreat&quot;&gt;released today&lt;/a&gt; by the Chicago Council on Global Affairs, for instance, respondents ranked Russia as the ninth most pressing threat to U.S. interests (tied with immigrants and refugees) and China as the 11th most pressing threat (tied with the rise of authoritarianism). Two-thirds of respondents preferred to deal with the rise of China through friendly cooperation and engagement, and just 30 percent preferred to limit its power. Among both Republicans and Democrats, more saw Chinese power as a threat in 1998 and 2002 than see it as such today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That survey is no outlier. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.people-press.org/2019/07/30/climate-change-and-russia-are-partisan-flashpoints-in-publics-views-of-global-threats/&quot;&gt;recent Pew Research Center poll&lt;/a&gt; asked Americans to rate seven threats, ranging from Iran and North Korea to climate change and the Islamic State (also known as ISIS). China came in fourth and Russia last. For the past decade, Americans have consistently ranked terrorism and cyberattacks as the two most pressing national security threats, as they did in the Chicago Council survey. Climate change increasingly finishes near the top, and while regional threats wax and wane in public consciousness, Americans still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2019/02/10/climate-change-still-seen-as-the-top-global-threat-but-cyberattacks-a-rising-concern/&quot;&gt;tend to rate&lt;/a&gt; North Korea as a bigger threat than the great powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These views correspond to specific policy preferences among the general public. A November 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reaganfoundation.org/media/299217/reagan-survey-full-charts-112918.pdf&quot;&gt;Reagan Institute poll&lt;/a&gt; asked where the United States should focus its military might. Possibly to the surprise of those seeking to extricate the United States from Middle Eastern distractions, it was not Europe or Asia that topped the list but the Middle East itself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogress.org/press/release/2019/05/06/469430/release-new-cap-poll-reveals-american-voters-really-want-u-s-foreign-policy-debate/&quot;&gt;Another poll&lt;/a&gt; by the Center for American Progress asked respondents to list their top foreign policy priorities. Stopping Russian interference in U.S. politics ranked behind guarding against terrorism, protecting American jobs, reducing illegal immigration, combating climate change, and dealing with Iran and North Korea. Taking on Chinese economic and military aggression ranked lower still, beneath all the same priorities as well as ending involvement in Middle East wars, fighting global poverty, and promoting trade. And whereas 95 percent of foreign policy elites would seek retaliation in the case of a Russian attack on a NATO ally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://egfound.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/EGF-WorldsApart-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;according to a recent Eurasia Group Foundation survey,&lt;/a&gt; only 54 percent of the public would do the same. Together, these surveys paint a picture of an American public much less concerned with great-power competition than with threats—such as terrorism, Iran, and North Korea—that policymakers have relegated to secondary status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;To the extent that long-term competition with Russia and China demands “whole of society” responses rather than just a set of new policies, a lack of public support courts danger.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible that the gap between elite and popular opinion will narrow over time as politicians adjust their focus to the concerns that most animate the public. Politicians and policymakers might begin to talk the terrorism-and-regional-threat talk while walking the great-power walk. Indeed, in his first State of the Union address, immediately following publication of the National Security Strategy, Trump emphasized the challenges not of great-power competition but of terrorism, North Korea, and illegal immigration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But another, perhaps more likely, possibility is that the gap will simply persist. For decades, elites have been more supportive of globalization, trade, foreign aid, and alliances than the American public. The problem is that gaps that persist invite backlash—a phenomenon the United States is arguably witnessing today with the backlash against globalization, trade, and alliances. And to the extent that long-term competition with Russia and China demands “whole of society” responses rather than just a set of new policies, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-07-18/how-confront-advancing-threat-china&quot;&gt;many in Washington&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-07-18/how-confront-advancing-threat-china&quot;&gt;now argue&lt;/a&gt;, a lack of public support courts danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington’s favored response seems to revolve around educating the American people about great-power threats. With China, the gap is already beginning to narrow: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thechicagocouncil.org/blog/running-numbers/lcc/elite-public-gap-china-may-be-decreasing&quot;&gt;a February survey from the Chicago Council&lt;/a&gt; showed that the percentage of respondents labeling the United States and China “mostly rivals” rose from 50 percent in March 2018 to 63 percent a year later. It is certainly tempting to borrow a page from Dean Acheson and make the Russia and China threats “clearer than the truth”—that is, painting them as critical and imminent—thereby stirring the country to action. The worry is that in doing so, elites will court overreaction and heighten anxiety among the public. The better course is to continually explain the nature of long-term great-power competition and connect it to specific actions Americans need to undertake to strengthen their position.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BALANCING THREATS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great-power competition is a fact of life in our current age, and it is likely to endure well into the future. Russia represents an acute near-term threat to the United States, largely but not exclusively because of its interference in American democracy. At the same time, China and the United States are locked in a long-term competition across military, economic, technological, and ideological spheres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But great-power competition cannot be the United States’ only focus, if for no other reason than the American people have other priorities. Left unattended, other threats—such as a mass-casualty terrorist attack on U.S. soil or a North Korean missile that falls close to the United States—could easily upend a carefully constructed set of policies aimed at countering Russia and China. In such a case, the temptation to embrace counterterrorism or rogue-state containment as the chief national security priority would become potentially irresistible—leaving the United States even more vulnerable to threats from Russia and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has become an axiom of American foreign policy that the United States can no longer do it all, everywhere—if ever it could. The threats are too manifold, the resources too scarce. Surely it’s true that difficult choices about priorities must be made. But it is also true that the United States cannot compete with China and Russia while at the same time minimizing or dismissing other critical threats, especially those that animate the public more than worries about great-power trajectories. How to balance these worthy priorities in a manageable and sustainable way will be the overarching challenge for U.S. foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;RICHARD FONTAINE&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is Chief Executive Officer of the Center for a New American Security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, September 9, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Richard Fontaine</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-09/great-power-competition-washingtons-top-priority-not-publics</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/09/rtx6y2ip.jpg?itok=RhTsrWCn</image>
 <media:description>Russian President Vladimir Putin and China’s President Xi Jinping shake hands at a meeting in June 2019 - Evgenia Novozhenina / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>China and Russia Don’t Keep Most Americans Awake at Night</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-11T02:11:43-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>How an Alliance System Withers</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-09/how-alliance-system-withers</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;For more than half a century, U.S. power in Asia has rested on the alliance system that Washington built in the years after World War II. Now, a dispute between Japan and South Korea—the two most important pillars of that system—threatens to undo decades of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But instead of seeking to actively mediate between its allies, Washington has largely watched from the sidelines—leaving the field to China, which has moved quickly to benefit from U.S. inaction. At a trilateral summit with the Japanese and South Korean foreign ministers in late August, for instance, China encouraged the two sides to at least put aside their differences long enough to make progress on a trilateral trade deal. This should give Washington pause. If, in the years ahead, the U.S. alliance system collapses, it is moments like this that will mark the beginning of the end: moments when Beijing, long intent on breaking U.S. alliances in Asia, proved more capable of managing and reinforcing regional order than a distracted United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WITH FRIENDS LIKE THESE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest round of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apnews.com/4c187890aa984313913e434996ee8751&quot;&gt;friction&lt;/a&gt; between South Korea and Japan began in the halls of South Korea’s supreme court. In the fall of 2018, the court ordered three Japanese companies to compensate South Koreans who claimed that they had been used as forced laborers in World War II. Tokyo, however, maintains that any claims to reparations for wartime abuses were settled by the $800 million in economic aid and loans it paid Seoul under a 1965 treaty. In March 2019, South Korean shop owners organized a nationwide boycott of Japanese goods. In response, the Japanese government restricted exports of three important chemicals used in the South Korean semiconductor industry, which accounts for a quarter of South Korea’s total exports. Japan also removed South Korea from its whitelist of preferred trading partners. Seoul responded in kind and went a step further, pulling out of a new intelligence-sharing agreement that had taken years to negotiate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese policymakers have recognized the rift between Seoul and Tokyo as a godsend. Fractures between two crucial U.S. allies make it harder for Washington to form a united front in peacetime or in a potential crisis. Such disunity also benefits China when it comes to dealing with North Korea, the nuclear-armed pariah state on its border. Here, Beijing favors sanctions relief, diplomatic engagement, and various economic inducements. So, too, does the current government of South Korea, but its space for engagement has been restricted by Washington and Tokyo, who prefer a more hawkish approach. Now, with the tripartite partnership under stress, China could try to make common cause with South Korea, disrupting Washington’s and Tokyo’s efforts to pursue hard-line policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Chinese policymakers have recognized the rift between Seoul and Tokyo as a godsend. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effects of the nascent Japanese–South Korean trade war on China less are less clear-cut. Tit-for-tat economic retaliation could set back negotiations on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/world/2019-07/04/c_1210177639.htm&quot;&gt;free-trade agreement&lt;/a&gt; between China, Japan, and South Korea, which Beijing has been promoting for years. But China could still capitalize on the economic fallout of the current dispute, particularly Japan’s decision to restrict the sale to South Korea of three chemicals used to produce microchips. South Korea’s valuable electronics industry, including the manufacturing giant Samsung, relies on these imports for its production. Companies will have to look for alternative suppliers, and China, which also produces the chemicals in question, can step in to fill the gap. The latest round of trade restrictions by Japan, in effect since August 28, may cause similar disruptions in other sectors of the South Korean economy, potentially increasing South Korea’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/f837f526-af78-11e9-8030-530adfa879c2&quot;&gt;economic reliance&lt;/a&gt; on Chinese exports. This dependence, in turn, could make South Korean more vulnerable to economic coercion, a tool Beijing has not hesitated to use in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also signs that China is using its political and security ties with Russia to exploit tensions between Tokyo and Seoul in a broader bid to undermine the U.S. regional alliance system. In July, China and Russia conducted their first ever joint air patrol, which included an incursion by a Russian aircraft into airspace over the Dokdo/Takeshima Islands disputed between South Korea and Japan. Likely aimed at testing U.S. allies’ air defenses, the patrol suggests greater willingness by China to challenge the U.S. military presence in Northeast Asia. Sino-Russian military cooperation in East Asia may become more sophisticated and frequent in pursuit of this goal, and with U.S. allies divided, Beijing will have less fear that it will suffer repercussions, reputational or otherwise, for such maneuvers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CHINA’S ENDGAME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China’s ultimate goal in exploiting the Japanese-South Korean feud is not as straightforward as it seems. Beijing wants tensions to escalate enough to undermine the U.S. alliance system in Asia, but it does not want the relationship between Seoul and Tokyo to sour to the point of complete estrangement. It just aspires for that relationship to be tethered to Beijing, not Washington. From its goal of a three-way free trade agreement to its vision for the Korean Peninsula, China wants to be at the center of its neighbors’ foreign policy considerations. Such a rebalancing of priorities and power in East Asia would put the U.S. regional position at serious risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Beijing has tried to cast the tensions between Japan and South Korea as evidence of poor U.S. leadership.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet China has been smart not to overplay its hand. So far, it hasn’t openly courted South Korea to abandon its alliance with the United States or launched its own campaign to punish Japan for World War II atrocities. Instead, it has tried to cast the tensions between Japan and South Korea as evidence of poor U.S. leadership—if the United States cannot serve as an effective &lt;a href=&quot;https://3w.huanqiu.com/a/de583b/7Ok30icBcRy?agt=35&quot;&gt;mediator&lt;/a&gt; between its allies, what good is it?—and present itself as a proactive peacemaker and more reliable partner than the United States. Earlier this year, Qiu Guohong, the Chinese ambassador to South Korea, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2019-01/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20190122_2-03.htm&quot;&gt;called for&lt;/a&gt; the two countries to work together to counter protectionism and unilateralism, a veiled reference to the Trump administration’s foreign and trade policies. Stronger Sino–South Korean &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/world/2014-07/03/c_126703364.htm&quot;&gt;ties&lt;/a&gt;, Qiu said, would show other U.S. allies in the region the benefits of protecting themselves from excessive U.S. interference in their domestic and foreign policy decisions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong U.S.-led alliances in East Asia have provided peace and security for more than half a century. Until recently, Chinese opposition to those alliances did not make them any less robust. But fraying ties between Tokyo and Seoul could embolden Beijing to seek to reshape the regional balance of power to its advantage. Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/04/world/asia/japan-south-korea-feud.html&quot;&gt;say&lt;/a&gt; that the Trump administration lost its chance to fix things by failing to get involved sooner. Perhaps, but given that the post–World War II regional order is at stake, the administration must redouble its efforts to ameliorate ties between Japan and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;BONNIE S. GLASER is Senior Adviser for Asia and Director of the China Power Project at the Center for Strategic and International Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ORIANA SKYLAR MASTRO is Assistant Professor of Security Studies at Georgetown University and Resident Scholar at the American Enterprise Institute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, September 9, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Bonnie S. Glaser and Oriana Skylar Mastro</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-09-09/how-alliance-system-withers</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/08/rts2n8dc.jpg?itok=HBFcJqWy</image>
 <media:description>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi with Japanese Foreign Minister Taro Kono and their South Korean counterpart Kang Kyung-wha in Beijing, August 2019 - Wu Hong / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>Washington Is Sleeping Through the Japanese-Korean Dispute. China Isn’t.</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-11T02:12:42-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Remembering Leslie H. Gelb</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-06/remembering-leslie-h-gelb</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;When word spread last weekend of &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/jmhfCqxMQYHZjZKFXzyvc?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the passing of Leslie H. Gelb&lt;/a&gt;—public servant, journalist, scholar, multipurpose éminence grise—&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/E-dYCrkM2RIElEPF4X5Zg?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;foreign-affairs Twitter lit up&lt;/a&gt; with tributes, as much about his wit and indefatigable mentoring as about his ideas and achievements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One admirer, the national-security expert and author &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/-GoPCv29QoixzxpIAcROc?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Micah Zenko&lt;/a&gt;, singled out &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/V8gVCwpR0mHK3KJu1piD4?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a signature insight of Gelb’s&lt;/a&gt;. In a book he co-authored with Richard K. Betts, called &lt;em&gt;The Irony of Vietnam: The System Worked&lt;/em&gt;, Gelb wrote, “Presidents have to make clear up and down the line that they want to hear criticisms and alternatives from their subordinates,” that “dissent should be institutionalized by rewards and promotions, not domesticated,” and that if a president speaks publicly and seriously about alternatives, it is easier for him to, if necessary, “change his mind.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice is good not just for presidents but for all leaders. And it goes to the heart of what made Gelb special. Funny, frank, down-to-earth, combative, affectionate—in short, complex—he was not only a creative thinker on the workings of power but a generous and effective mentor, even to many with whom he sometimes clashed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gelb prioritized mentoring and raised it to an art form. It is hard to imagine how he had the time during &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/aQMQCyPJwrCZ5ZqFPgbat?domain=nytimes.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an extraordinary career&lt;/a&gt;: at the Department of Defense, he oversaw the compilation of the internal report that became known as the Pentagon Papers. Then, among other things, he served as a national security reporter, deputy editorial-page editor, op-ed editor, and columnist at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. He headed the Council on Foreign Relations from 1993 to 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet along the way, he seeded the worlds of foreign policy, journalism, and government with younger people whom he empowered, including many women. He kept up decades-long relationships with people like me, whom he met as entry-level assistants or very junior colleagues and steered—not to say badgered—toward adventures and opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Gelb mentee, it seems, has a particular gruff phrase to recall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Keep pissing people off.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Always have a strategy. I never take a piss without having a strategy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Too much of what passes for policy is wish lists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Strike while the iron is hot—YOU. MUST. STRIKE.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, the terse announcement of an unexpected opportunity: “Dick Holbrooke’s gonna call you.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before it was an institutional piety, Gelb particularly sought to hire, promote, and mentor women. His was a conscious effort to redress inequality in foreign affairs, and it came of the recognition that excluding women meant missing great talent. Recent public focus on bad male bosses makes Gelb stand out all the more. He hired a lot of young women staffers—for their brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Long before it was an institutional piety, Gelb particularly sought to hire, promote, and mentor women.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days since Gelb’s death, I have exchanged memories with some of these mentees. “I have a wonderful memory of sitting in a darkened room, as his eyesight failed, while he read me the riot act for not standing up for myself more, not owning my own authority,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/ckNpCzpx6KH6o6QuMSgks?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heather Hurlburt&lt;/a&gt;, who runs a politics and policy project at New America and was executive director of the center-left National Security Network, whose board Gelb chaired. “He made me feel like I&#039;d landed in a foreign policy remake of &lt;em&gt;The Karate Kid&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid-2000s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/M1ThCAD96PS4A4LtBRcxf?domain=twitter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rosa Brooks&lt;/a&gt;, the author of &lt;em&gt;How Everything Became War and the Military Became Everything&lt;/em&gt;, took a surprising cold call from Gelb, who asked her to help organize a conference series. This work helped lead her to a job in the Obama administration as counselor to the under secretary of defense for policy. “Les just popped up in my life out of nowhere as a sort of guardian angel,” Brooks told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me, I was Gelb’s last editorial assistant at the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; before he moved to the Council, in 1993. I wasn’t supposed to get that job. How I did says a lot about Gelb. I cut out some of his foreign affairs columns and marked them up with a pencil, showing how I would have line-edited to make them read better. I was a 21-year-old English major. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader, he hired me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, he was a reference for, and adviser on, every job and fellowship I ever had. As a boss, he was open not only to teaching but to learning from the younger and lowlier. He encouraged dissent, resistance, even criticism, while still being decisive and exacting. He taught me much of what I value and try to emulate as a boss, employee, colleague, and mentor: being direct, clear, challenging, friendly, and respectful, while remaining open to change and to disagreeing productively and with a sense of humor. He had high standards and a passion for the subject and the mission at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made Gelb unusual for an expert wielder of power was his ability to change, absorb criticism, and listen. Once, 27 years ago, I was on my way to meet someone powerful. He “warned” me that she was a lesbian. I said, “Then you should warn me every time I meet a powerful man.” Right then he said that I was right, that he was out of line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such was, if you will, the irony of Les. He inhabited and mastered the clubby, white, male, bipartisan foreign policy world of his day, but he sought to infuse it with new and different people. He retained what Hurlburt called some “prejudices typical to many of his peers”: at dinners in recent years, he’d typically demand, “What is it that’s wrong with Islam?” Yet he welcomed argument on that point, and encouraged and empowered people who explicitly challenged his preconceptions and even criticized him for them. Brooks called him, affectionately, “a totally unreconstructed old-school male,” and told me, “He would use random gendered metaphors for foreign policy, but he could always take it if you said, ‘Les, that’s totally inappropriate.’ It didn’t stop him from being a major champion for women.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;What made Gelb unusual for an expert wielder of power was his ability to change, absorb criticism, and listen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gelb knew what it was to be an outsider. Raised by Hungarian Jewish immigrants who ran a deli in New Rochelle, he worked his way through college as a dishwasher and valet parking attendant. As the author George Packer noted in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/3LkFCDkJq9IqlqNhv6M_G?domain=amazon.com&quot;&gt;biography of Richard Holbrooke&lt;/a&gt;, when Gelb made it to graduate school “he had no idea what his teachers were talking about.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I showed up to work for Gelb, I loved international affairs, foreign cultures, and languages, but I knew nothing about the policy world where he was an insider. He probably saw right away that I hadn’t really heard of him. I hadn’t even known “Leslie H. Gelb” ’s gender when I applied, and when he told me to scan the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; every day I thought he meant &lt;em&gt;The New York Post&lt;/em&gt;. But he took me seriously. He wanted my input from day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His best boss trick was to make me rise to occasions. He would hand out big responsibilities—having me not just line-edit but help to report and shape columns—making me want to deserve them. He wrote what seemed like extravagant recommendation letters that I strove to make true. He would spring a dead-on diagnosis of something I needed to improve or shoot for, but delivered with a twinkle that ensured support, in a manner that was totally disarming and motivating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, Gelb mostly worked from home in sweats, giving me his dark-wood &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; office and old Rolodex, summoning me to Barney Greengrass or the Popover Café to brief him on my Bosnia or South China Sea research. Once, when he was in Seoul, I asked if he wanted research on local restaurants and cultural sites. He wasn’t interested. (He stuck with Greengrass, committed to his deli roots.) But he later saw, and valued, that my habit of cultural immersion made me a good international reporter. After all, he had diagnosed Americans’ lack of understanding of Vietnamese people as the cause of that disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the end, Gelb was Gelb. He pissed off many, as he would say, with his proposal to &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/Uk9hCpYXZQSm3m1uPhqyz?domain=nytimes.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;federalize Iraq&lt;/a&gt;. He supported the initial American invasion. But—rare in his circle—he accepted responsibility when things went wrong. He called the mistake “symptomatic of unfortunate tendencies” among experts to support wars “to retain political and professional credibility.” And with his forays into blogging and working groups on new approaches to foreign policy, Hurlburt noted to me, “He did better than most at changing with the times.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of his life, I saw Gelb only every few years. But I’d already spent enough time with him and his wife, Judy, at their warm, brainy gatherings to make them a model of family, social, and intellectual partnership. When Les got his dream job at the Council, the Gelbs even worried how the move would affect 22-year-old me: he’d just persuaded me to stay with him another year at the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my evaluation, he wrote that I would make a great &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reporter someday. I came back 15 years later, after stints in Moscow and Philadelphia and Boston and Baghdad and Jerusalem and Tehran and Kabul. At the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; I have covered Queens and Syria and the Middle East and now climate. I hope I made him proud. I know he still wanted more. (I’m working on it, Les.) He, too, surely had more to do. But he had a profound influence on many people, and in times of great uncertainty in international affairs, they are carrying on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;ANNE BARNARD, a former Edward R. Murrow press fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, covers climate and environment at The New York Times, where she served as Beirut bureau chief from 2012-2018. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, September 6, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Anne Barnard </dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-06/remembering-leslie-h-gelb</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/05/tgelb_portrait_final.jpg?itok=xyNmcAZK</image>
 <media:description>Creative Commons</media:description>
 <subtitle>Mentor to a Changing Foreign Policy World</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T08:53:10-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Nineteenth-Century Nihilists Foretold Our Era</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-06/nineteenth-century-nihilists-foretold-our-era</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Most historians view the French Revolution as the source of the ideologies that have shaped the modern and postmodern eras. For any ism—from liberalism, conservatism, and communism to nationalism, totalitarianism, and anarchism—historians can make the case that it springs from the cascade of events that began in 1789. An ism that usually fails to make the list, however, is one that now seems to be on the tip of every pundit’s pen—namely, nihilism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the odder footnotes to the revolution, the Baron de Cloots, Jean-Baptiste du Val-de-Grâce—better known by his pen name, Anacharsis Cloots, if not by his chosen title as “Orator of the Human Race”—embraced the term “nihilism.” Determined that the fledgling French Republic be truly secular, Cloots insisted that its citizens avoid all reference to God. Even atheists, he warned, by their denial of God’s existence keep God’s name alive. For this reason, he intoned, the “republic of the rights of man is strictly speaking neither theist nor atheist, but nihilist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the aspiring nihilist did not live long enough to realize his hope for establishing a republic on the moon—Cloots literally lost his head during the Terror—the term he introduced has enjoyed a long and varied life. Indeed, it is now experiencing something of a renaissance. Even the most casual consumer of news keeps stumbling across the term, especially when it comes to the theater of American politics. Rather like neighboring tribes that, according to anthropologists, accuse each other of engaging in cannibalism, our political parties denounce each other for engaging in nihilism. Victor Davis Hanson of the Hoover Institution disparages the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hoover.org/research/new-nihilism&quot;&gt;new nihilism&lt;/a&gt;” of the Democratic Party, while Alex Pareene of &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt; decries the Senate majority leader, Mitch McConnell, as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/153275/mitch-mcconnell-profile-nihilist-chief&quot;&gt;nihilist in chief&lt;/a&gt;.” A Google search of “Trump” and “nihilism” sparks well more than half a million hits, crowding the screen from both sides of the political spectrum: the conservative columnist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/06/opinion/trump-el-paso-dayton-shootings.html&quot;&gt;Ross Douthat&lt;/a&gt; reserves “nihilist in chief” for the president, while the liberal columnist E. J. Dionne, as if nihilism alone were not bad enough, castigates Trump for his “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/global-opinions/the-steep-price-of-trumps-incoherent-nihilism/2019/08/14/ce83664a-bed0-11e9-a5c6-1e74f7ec4a93_story.html?noredirect=on&quot;&gt;incoherent nihilism&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet we must not conclude that nihilism is in the eye of the belittler. “Fascism,” for example, has long been treated as a rhetorical rod for bashing others over the head—such that we forget that the word refers to a clear and uncompromising conception of political and social life. So, too, with nihilism, though on a grander scale. With the bicentenary of Fyodor Dostoyevsky’s birthday just around the corner—the Russian government, academic institutions, and global organizations such as UNESCO are well into planning the celebrations for 2021—where better to turn for a grasp of a notion so elusive yet so vital?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, Dostoyevsky neither coined the term nor gave it currency. The word was loosely applied to semiclandestine student groups in mid-nineteenth-century Russia, at one another’s throats over strategy but united in their determination to overthrow the repressive tsarist state. The publication of Ivan Turgenev’s &lt;em&gt;Fathers and Children&lt;/em&gt; in 1862 firmly entrenched the term in the popular imagination. The novel’s charismatic protagonist, Evgeny Vasilich Bazarov, embodies a heroic conception of nihilism. When asked just who or what is a nihilist, Bazarov proudly replies: “We act on the basis of what we recognize as useful. . . . Nowadays the most useful thing of all is rejection—we reject.” When his shocked interlocutor insists that the construction of a better world is also important, Bazarov cuts him short: “That’s not for us to do. . . . First, the ground must be cleared.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appalled by the terrorist activities of the young nihilists on whom Turgenev based Bazarov, Dostoyevsky transformed their political doctrine into something much larger and more dreadful. In his later novels, ranging from &lt;em&gt;Crime and Punishment&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;The Devils&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;The Brothers Karamazov,&lt;/em&gt; Dostoyevsky suggested that the true specter haunting Europe was not communism but nihilism. It was an ism unlike any other insofar as it held that the carcass of the past was not worth preserving, the misery of the present demanded that one act, and the promise of the future permitted one to do whatever was necessary to bring it about. Whereas Turgenev’s Bazarov made pronouncements, Dostoyevsky’s Raskolnikov made plans and acted upon them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dostoyevsky drew nihilism from the realms of politics and ethics into that of metaphysics. If everything we have thought is a tale told by an idiot, if everything we have done amounts to a hill of beans, we find ourselves unmoored not just from morality but from the possibility of meaning itself. Everything is permitted, as Ivan Karamazov declares, when you believe in nothing and hold nothing to be important. Whereas the political nihilism that hovers over the characters in &lt;em&gt;Fathers and Children&lt;/em&gt; disavows political and social institutions, the metaphysical nihilism that hounds the actors in &lt;em&gt;The Brothers Karamazov&lt;/em&gt; disavows existence itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Dostoyevsky and Nietzsche offered prescriptions along with their descriptions of our common predicament. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to grasp the relevance of this claim for our own era, we need to glance at the work of the man whose reading of Dostoyevsky led to the definition of nihilism with which we still grapple. In 1887, Friedrich Nietzsche excitedly wrote to a friend about a discovery he had just made: “I knew nothing about Dostoyevsky until a few weeks ago. . . . The instinct of affinity (or what shall I call it?) spoke to me instantaneously—my joy was beyond bounds.” As Nietzsche perceived, the Russian novelist had not just blasted political nihilism but also detonated the enlightened foundations, built with the mortar of reason and means of technology, into smithereens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same year, while still reading Dostoyevsky, Nietzsche posed the $64,000 question: “What does nihilism mean?” Nietzsche being Nietzsche, he already had the answer, one he emblazoned in italics: &lt;em&gt;“That the highest values devaluate themselves.”&lt;/em&gt; By “values,” Nietzsche means nothing less than truth and reason. The acid of reason, by dissolving every belief we ever held, ultimately dissolves itself. It seems to abandon us in a cosmic dead end, leaving us with a dismal consolation prize—the paradoxical affirmation that “there is simply no &lt;em&gt;true world&lt;/em&gt;.” What this offers someone who is dying for meaning, of course, is what an empty glass offers someone who is dying of thirst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Dostoyevsky and Nietzsche offered prescriptions along with their descriptions of our common predicament. For the former, the answer was religious faith—and not just any religion, but specifically Eastern Orthodox Christianity—while for the latter, the answer was aesthetic faith, or the belief that art alone could impose meaning on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for many of us today, these answers come up short. We live in a world that bears an uncanny resemblance to the one foreseen by Dostoyevsky and Nietzsche. It is steeped in claims and counterclaims of fake news and steered by a president who has made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2019/08/12/president-trump-has-made-false-or-misleading-claims-over-days/&quot;&gt;more than 12,000 false claims&lt;/a&gt; since entering office. In our world, presidential advisers have graduated from deriding “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2004/10/17/magazine/faith-certainty-and-the-presidency-of-george-w-bush.html&quot;&gt;reality-based communities&lt;/a&gt;” to deciding that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2017/01/22/kellyanne-conway-says-donald-trumps-team-has-alternate-facts-which-pretty-much-says-it-all/&quot;&gt;alternative facts&lt;/a&gt;” are all the facts we need. Ours is a world where the claims of objective truth hardly resonate amid the clamor of tribal truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, the nihilist is not to be confused with the narcissist or fabulist, the hired gun or hanger-on. On the contrary, a nihilist offers a kind of constancy and hope. “A nihilist is a man who judges of the world as it is that it ought not to be,” Nietzsche declared, “and of the world as it ought to be that it does not exist.” Though this observation runs against the interpretive grain of most Nietzscheans, it suggests that a nihilist—Nietzsche described himself, after all, as the “first perfect European nihilist”—takes the full measure of the situation, plumbs its significance, and searches for an answer. Moreover, and again unlike the narcissist, Nietzsche’s nihilist seeks to overcome that situation by mastering, not by cosseting, the self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither Dostoyevsky nor Nietzsche pretended to be a political theorist. One suspects, though, that if they had, they would have thought twice before dismissing the ideals of modern democracies. We are witness to a political world shorn of the values that Dostoyevsky declared useless without God and that Nietzsche pronounced dead along with God. If our current situation is as dire as many believe, we might leave to others the task of sorting out the status of God and instead wager on the values of the world as it once was and again needs to be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROBERT ZARETSKY is a professor of modern French history at the Honors College, University of Houston, and the author of &lt;em&gt;Catherine &amp;amp; Diderot: The Empress, The Philosopher, and the Fate of the Enlightenment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, September 6, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Robert Zaretsky</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-09-06/nineteenth-century-nihilists-foretold-our-era</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/06/trumpera.jpg?itok=VF7RVvPn</image>
 <media:description>A “March for Truth” protest in Los Angeles in June 2017 - John Fredricks / REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>Why the Age of Alternative Facts Might Have Unnerved Even Nietzsche</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T18:02:26-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Pope Francis’ Holy Diplomacy in Ukraine</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/ukraine/2019-09-05/pope-francis-holy-diplomacy-ukraine</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The Holy See and the United States once had a close partnership. Under U.S. President Ronald Reagan, for instance, the CIA provided &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,159069,00.html&quot;&gt;regular briefings&lt;/a&gt; to Pope John Paul II, as the Vatican coordinated with Washington to support democratic change in Poland. Those days are now over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing exemplifies the decline of this special relationship like Pope Francis’ diplomacy in Ukraine. In the last year, U.S.-Russian rivalries have played out in that country through the division between factions of the Orthodox Church. In the last year, the Ukrainian Orthodox Church decisively split from the Moscow patriarchate, with the explicit approval of the United States. Francis did not follow the U.S. lead and instead cautioned Ukrainian Catholics not to meddle in the Orthodox proxy war. The pope has used his relationships with important players on all sides of the dispute—including in Moscow—to calm nerves. He has succeeded insofar as he has coaxed the antagonists into seeing one another’s humanity, which cut through the hostility in turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francis’ discreet, behind-the-scenes mediation is of a piece with the approach to diplomacy he outlined in &lt;em&gt;Evangelii Gaudium&lt;/em&gt;, his first papal exhortation, in 2013. In that exhortation, Francis emphasized four principles: that the whole is greater than the part, that unity prevails over conflict, that realities are more important than ideas, and that time is greater than space. Although abstract on first glance, the rules genuinely summarize his strategy, and reflect his desire to remain neutral among competing geopolitical powers, including the United States. This neutrality, in turn, is helping to restore the Holy See to its status as a major diplomatic player.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WHOLE AND FREE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francis’ first guiding principle—that the whole is greater than the parts—can be seen in his reluctance to take sides within Ukraine’s religious conflict. Catholics make up no more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/12/19/5-facts-about-catholics-in-europe/&quot;&gt;ten percent of Ukraine’s population&lt;/a&gt;, but they have long played an outsized role shaping national identity. The largest Catholic community is the Ukrainian Greek Catholic Church (UGCC), created in 1596 when a group of Orthodox bishops agreed to recognize Rome while maintaining Byzantine-rite liturgy. (Ukraine also has much smaller Latin and Ruthenian Catholic communities—a legacy of western Ukraine’s history as Polish and Austro-Hungarian territory.)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UGCC has firmly attached itself to the pro-Western side of Ukraine’s internal conflict. One might have expected Francis to do so as well. In Buenos Aires, he was friendly with a UGCC archbishop, a former Soviet soldier named Sviatoslav Shevchuk, who at that time served a sizable Argentine diaspora. Shevchuk now leads the UGCC and was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncregister.com/daily-news/ukraines-revolution-of-dignity-and-its-predators&quot;&gt;prominent supporter&lt;/a&gt; of the 2014 Maidan protests that touched off the current conflict. Shevchuk has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royaldoors.net/2014/06/ukraine-is-on-pilgrimage-thank-you-for-walking-with-us/&quot;&gt;encouraged&lt;/a&gt; Christians to confront “terrorist violence and overt military aggression from abroad,” a clear reference to Russia’s military intervention in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pope has &lt;a href=&quot;https://catholicherald.co.uk/commentandblogs/2018/06/19/why-is-rome-sidelining-the-ukrainian-catholics/&quot;&gt;rejected&lt;/a&gt; Shevchuk’s confrontational approach. When the archbishop described the conflict as a Russian “invasion,” Francis responded by condemning it as a “fratricidal war.” In February 2015, the pope politely told his Ukrainian bishops to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncronline.org/blogs/francis-chronicles/pope-francis-tells-ukrainian-bishops-stay-out-politics&quot;&gt;stay out of politics&lt;/a&gt;, explaining that “the sense of justice and truth, before being political, is moral.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Francis, all conflict can be traced to interests, whether military, economic, or those related to national pride. But he is no more suspicious of Russian imperialism than of what he sees as U.S. imperialism—both Moscow and Washington, in his view, are equally self-interested and destructive. He therefore refuses to prioritize one group of Christians over another. The whole of Christianity is sacred, so peace must be found among its warring parts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;THE UNIVERSAL CHURCH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francis’ second principle emphasizes unity over conflict. The unity he means to preserve is not only among fellow Catholics but also between Catholics and their Orthodox brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eastern Orthodoxy is a family of 14 autonomous local churches. The largest of these is the Russian Orthodox Church, with more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewforum.org/2017/11/08/orthodox-christianity-in-the-21st-century/&quot;&gt;100 million believers&lt;/a&gt;. In the 1960s, Rome sought to heal the schism with Eastern Orthodoxy, but the Russian church was locked behind the Iron Curtain. Pope Paul VI &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apostolicpilgrimage.org/historicmeeting&quot;&gt;made peace&lt;/a&gt; with Athenagoras, the patriarch of Constantinople and “first among equals” within international Orthodoxy. In tandem, the U.S. government, which did not trust the communist-controlled leaders of the Russian church, promoted Athenagoras, a U.S. citizen, as global Orthodoxy’s main man. When Athenagoras was chosen as patriarch in 1949, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.goarch.org/blog/-/blogs/truman-athenagoras-and-world-orthodoxy-an-historical-alternative-to-current-us-relations-with-constantinople-part-two&quot;&gt;arrived in Istanbul&lt;/a&gt; on President Harry Truman’s presidential plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pope Francis has grown particularly close to the current patriarch of Constantinople, Bartholomew. They’ve traveled together in the Holy Lands and Greek islands and visited each other at home, and this June Francis gave a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecupatria.org/2019/07/01/pope-francis-of-rome-gave-relics-of-saint-peter-to-the-church-of-constantinople/&quot;&gt;relic of St. Peter&lt;/a&gt; to Constantinople. Yet Francis and his diplomats are also close to Patriarch Kirill and the Russian Orthodox Church. In this, he builds on the work of his two predecessors: in 1989, Pope John Paul II agreed to restore &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/1989/12/02/gorbachev-pope-meet-agree-on-diplomatic-relations/e1f347a2-71cc-4648-b580-9a1f96a92de9/?noredirect=on&quot;&gt;some diplomatic ties&lt;/a&gt; with the Soviet Union, and in 2010, Benedict XVI—who saw a deeply Christian Russia as an ally against the secular relativism of western Europe—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/russia-and-holy-see-establish-full-diplomatic-ties&quot;&gt;fully normalized relations&lt;/a&gt; between Moscow and the Holy See. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fa-stage-files.s3.amazonaws.com/styles/large-crop-landscape/s3/images/articles/2019/09/04/rtx66am0.jpg?itok=ZqGUzYtT&quot; alt=&quot;Francis meets with Bartholomew in the Vatican, May 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Francis meets with Bartholomew in the Vatican, May 2018 - Reuters&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Francis, the Vatican’s relationship with the Russian church—now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carnegiecouncil.org/publications/articles_papers_reports/727&quot;&gt;backed by the Russian state&lt;/a&gt;—has flowered. Partly as a result of the pope’s pastoral prudence regarding Ukraine, in 2016, Putin green-lighted the first personal encounter between Francis and Kirill. At Havana’s international airport, the two leaders signed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://w2.vatican.va/content/francesco/en/speeches/2016/february/documents/papa-francesco_20160212_dichiarazione-comune-kirill.html&quot;&gt;joint declaration&lt;/a&gt; expressing shared religious, social, and political views. Three of the declaration’s 30 points pertained to the Ukrainian conflict, and the leaders pledged to hold the line against either church’s “taking part in the confrontation.” The UGCC leadership &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.romereports.com/en/2016/03/07/pope-listens-to-complaints-from-ukrainian-archbishop-of-the-text-he-signed-with-kirill/&quot;&gt;fumed&lt;/a&gt;, but in the pope’s view, pursuing Christian unity—Christ’s own last wish—requires Rome to function in a balanced, loving way. If Francis had openly leaned toward Lvov, he would have fanned the flames of religious war. Instead, he has preached restraint to those over whom he has most influence, UGCC leaders, hoping to model behavior for the Russian Orthodox Church in its relations with the faithful in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moscow and Constantinople are now dueling over the status of a new Ukrainian Orthodox Church, which Bartholomew declared autocephalous (or independent from the Russian Orthodox Church) in 2018. The Russian church &lt;a href=&quot;https://mospat.ru/en/2018/10/28/news165801/&quot;&gt;claims&lt;/a&gt; that Bartholomew was strong-armed into the declaration by former Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hurriyetdailynews.com/us-in-support-of-bartholomews-stance-on-ukrainian-church-137279&quot;&gt;U.S. government&lt;/a&gt;. U.S. Secretary of State Mike Pompeo has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/move-towards-ukrainian-autocephaly/&quot;&gt;declared&lt;/a&gt; Washington’s support for autocephaly in Ukraine. And again Francis ordered Ukrainian Catholics not to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;KEEPING IT REAL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third of Francis’ principles is that realities are more important than ideas. Living through Argentina’s “dirty war,” Francis (then known as Jorge Bergoglio) grew to despise ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has brought this attitude to Ukraine, where he prefers to address the realities of poverty and war-weariness rather than adjudicate competing claims. Between 2016 and 2018, he raised $18 million for some 900,000 Ukrainians, most of them Orthodox, who either resided in the conflict zone or had been displaced from their homes. Food, medicine, social services to treat PTSD, and renovations to winterize homes and install boilers were the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humandevelopment.va/en/progetti/il-papa-per-l-ucraina.html&quot;&gt;main expenditures&lt;/a&gt;. The aid has been directly delivered to desperate people and supervised by the papal nuncio, who said the pope &lt;a href=&quot;https://insidethevatican.com/news/newsflash/letter-18-2019-vatican-nuncio-to-ukraine-interview/&quot;&gt;told him&lt;/a&gt; that his role is more charitable than political.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the &lt;a href=&quot;https://international.la-croix.com/news/ukraines-two-orthodox-churches-compete-for-hearts-and-minds/10614&quot;&gt;ecclesiastical conflict&lt;/a&gt; over the autocephaly of the Ukrainain Orthodox Church, Vatican diplomats don’t think the faithful are easily manipulated. The majority of Ukrainians belong to the Orthodox church affiliated with the Moscow patriarchate and will not casually leave their bishops and local priests. And many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/ukraine/2019-03-18/risk-ethnic-conflict-growing-ukraine&quot;&gt;Orthodox believers&lt;/a&gt; do not feel compelled to declare themselves members of one “brand” or another. Indeed, since Poroshenko’s defeat in the presidential election this April, the Ukrainian government has abandoned its attempts to force Moscow-affiliated parishes to join the autocephalous Ukrainian church. In July, Ukraine’s new president, Volodymyr Zelensky, tweeted, “I urge the leaders of the churches to dialogue, in order to unite the faith, and not divide Ukrainians. In unity is our strength and our future.” It was a statement after Francis’ own heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE IT SLOW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francis believes that God’s hand is shown in history, and that his job is to encourage reconciliation without trying to control the outcome. With patience and persistence, good things evolve over time. This conviction—that time is greater than space—is the fourth principle shaping the Holy See’s diplomacy. In the pope’s view, politics is preoccupied with taking positions, gaining advantage, and occupying space in a manner that mimics military action. He prefers to advance slowly, through personal encounters that gradually build love and mutual respect. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Francis believes that his job is to encourage reconciliation without trying to control the outcome.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent polling data bear out Francis’ intuition. As time passes, regular Ukrainians are becoming less polarized and more willing to “reconcile diversity,” to use Francis’ phrase from Evangelii Gaudium. Earlier this year, a Kiev &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kiis.com.ua/?lang=rus&amp;amp;cat=reports&amp;amp;id=795&amp;amp;page=1&quot;&gt;public opinion poll&lt;/a&gt; found that among Ukrainians, favorable feelings toward Russia had increased from 30 percent in 2015 to 57 percent today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CHRISTIAN DIPLOMACY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pope’s neutral line on Ukraine is the latest example of how Catholic doctrine and Vatican diplomacy have diverged from U.S. foreign policy preferences since the end of the Cold War. Pope John Paul II, for instance, sent top diplomats to personally dissuade U.S. President George W. Bush from invading Iraq, prophetically warning Bush that the war would lead to countless casualties and long-term regional turmoil, including the scapegoating and repression of Christian communities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Vatican’s view, the United States’ post–Cold War foreign policy has been overly militaristic and dismissive of the benefits of peaceful diplomacy. There have been notable exceptions—Rome strongly supported the Obama administration’s nuclear deal with Iran and its rapprochement with Cuba. In general, however, the Holy See is concerned that the United States has stopped exercising its once significant moral influence as a country striving to calm nerves, encourage liberal order, and facilitate peace, opting instead for counterproductive bellicosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the United States’ aggressiveness has opened up space for the Vatican. Between America’s loss of prestige and the multiplication of conflicts around the world, there are fewer disinterested actors aiming to defuse conflicts and create space for alternative solutions. This week, the pope is embarking on a three-country tour of southeastern Africa, where he will deploy dialogue—informed by the four principles sketched above—as his primary method of diplomacy. Francis’ itinerary, which includes a visit to Mozambique to encourage a new peace agreement and a trip to Madagascar to bolster the country’s fragile transition back to constitutional government, suggests that there is no shortage of places eager for the Holy Father’s input. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;VICTOR GAETAN is Senior International Correspondent for &lt;em&gt;The National Catholic Register&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, September 5, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Victor Gaetan</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/ukraine/2019-09-05/pope-francis-holy-diplomacy-ukraine</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/04/rtx6w1ee.jpg?itok=TmoUgUJQ</image>
 <media:description>Pope Francis greets members of the Ukrainian army at the Vatican, May 2019 - Remo Casilli / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>Why Washington and the Vatican Don’t See Eye to Eye</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T09:26:49-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A Deal With the Taliban Is Only the First Step Toward Peace</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-09-05/deal-taliban-only-first-step-toward-peace</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;After months of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-03-01/negotiations-are-best-way-end-war-afghanistan&quot;&gt;closed-door negotiations&lt;/a&gt; in Doha, Qatar, the United States appears close to finalizing a deal with the Taliban that would end Washington’s 18-year war in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/regions/afghanistan&quot;&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;. The agreement would reportedly set a conditional timetable for the United States to withdraw its troops from Afghanistan in exchange for Taliban commitments to suppress terrorist groups and open peace talks with their fellow Afghans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal is controversial. Supporters (and I am one of them) view the agreement as far preferable to the status quo—a bloody battlefield stalemate—and a necessary first step toward any deal among Afghans to end the war. Critics worry that the deal sells out Washington’s Afghan allies, places &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-02-21/taliban-making-pledge-it-cannot-keep&quot;&gt;naive trust in an extremist group&lt;/a&gt;, and provides cover for a troop withdrawal that Trump wants regardless of whether it makes diplomatic or military sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, though, no U.S.-Taliban agreement will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-08-26/diplomacy-cant-solve-all-afghanistans-problems&quot;&gt;determine Afghanistan’s future&lt;/a&gt;. Talks with the Taliban, the Afghan government, and other Afghan parties are far more important, and these are expected to start soon after the U.S.-Taliban deal is announced. Thus the most vital concession that the United States’ lead negotiator, Special Envoy Zalmay Khalilzad, has wrung from the Taliban is not the group’s well-publicized promise not to support terrorism; rather, it is the group’s agreement to at last negotiate with other Afghans, which for years it has refused to do until a timetable was in place for U.S. troops to withdraw. If, as reported, Khalilzad has negotiated a conditional timetable for withdrawal, the actual departure of U.S. troops would be contingent on the Taliban continuing these negotiations in good faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the intra-Afghan talks that follow any U.S.-Afghan agreement succeed, stability is possible in Afghanistan and the U.S.-Taliban deal will have been a necessary precursor. If they fail, this initial deal’s virtues may be for naught. The most important phase in this peace process is just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MAPPING THE TRANSITION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary mission of intra-Afghan talks will be to map out a transition period that ends the war and brings the Taliban into Afghanistan’s political system. This will almost inevitably require the Afghan parties to address three issues from the beginning: Afghanistan’s forthcoming presidential election, the precise mechanism for incorporating the Taliban, and a cease-fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan’s presidential election is currently scheduled for September 28, but Afghans are split on whether it should take place. President Ashraf Ghani, the front-runner, wants to hold the election so that he can win a fresh mandate for negotiations. The Taliban argue for canceling the vote, which they consider an illegitimate product of the post-2001 “occupation” of Afghanistan. Many other Afghan leaders, notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/reviews/review-essay/2016-10-12/corleones-kabul&quot;&gt;former President Hamid Karzai&lt;/a&gt;, hope to cancel or delay the election because they consider peace a greater priority and fear—rightly—extensive electoral fraud and violence. The election may now be so near that a cancellation is unrealistic, but the parties are likely to debate the issue in the first days of intra-Afghan talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not the election proceeds, Afghans will need to negotiate a process for the Taliban to transition into mainstream politics. Ghani wants the current Afghan government to preside over any transition, while the Taliban and many of Ghani’s other rivals want to create a new interim government. Either way, Afghan leaders will need to define what positions will be open to Taliban representatives. The negotiators must also agree on what the interim government’s core tasks will be: for instance, reviewing the Afghan constitution, devising a program to reintegrate today’s fighters into society, and reforming the security forces. Finally, the Afghan leaders will need to agree on how and when the transition will end and how any interim authority will be dissolved, whether through an election or a national conference to choose its successor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fa-stage-files.s3.amazonaws.com/styles/large-crop-landscape/s3/images/articles/2019/09/05/rts2ovu3.jpg?itok=tcVxg6Xx&quot; alt=&quot;Khalilzad (second from right) meets with Afghan Chief Executive Abdullah Abdullah in Kabul, September 2019&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Khalilzad (second from right) meets with Afghan Chief Executive Abdullah Abdullah in Kabul, September 2019 - Reuters&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top objective for most non-Taliban Afghan leaders will be to negotiate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2018-09-07/taliban-prepared-make-peace&quot;&gt;an enduring cease-fire&lt;/a&gt;. Like most insurgents at war with governments, the Taliban view violence as their primary source of leverage. They therefore have an incentive to postpone a permanent cease-fire until the political questions have been resolved. This means that although nearly all Afghans want an immediate end to the fighting—and Khalilzad has emphasized that a cease-fire must be a part of any final deal—an actual cease-fire may have to wait until the start of a transitional period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEFINING THE FUTURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond these immediate issues, intra-Afghan discussions will need to broach the larger questions at the heart of the war—those concerning Afghanistan’s longer-term political future and how the country can begin to rebuild after nearly four decades of civil war. These questions may take years to fully resolve but finding some early convergence will be critical for a successful peace process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most basic question concerns Afghanistan’s form of government. Nearly all non-Taliban Afghans embrace the post-2001 democratic system, whatever its flaws. Although Taliban leaders rarely demand the literal return of their draconian 1996–2001 emirate, in which the group banned elections and imposed a strict form of sharia law, they reject the legitimacy of the post-2001 system and insist on replacing it with something more “Islamic.” If the Taliban decide that a compromise is possible on this point, they may propose some new balance of secular and religious institutions akin to the Iranian system, in which unelected clerics exercise a check on elected officials. If so, the most important debate in the entire negotiation might be over the respective authorities of elected and religious leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly in light of this fundamental divergence over the role and interpretation of religion, the negotiators will undoubtedly need to address the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2016-05-30/schools-under-siege&quot;&gt;fundamental rights of Afghan citizens&lt;/a&gt;, especially women, who were prevented from working or attending school the last time the Taliban held power. Afghan women’s groups are adamant that the country must not revive the abuses of the Taliban regime, and most Afghan leaders at least claim they will prioritize women’s rights in any negotiation. The Taliban are quick to assert that they, too, will protect women’s rights—albeit “in accordance with Islam.” Basic rights for women are now guaranteed by the 2004 Constitution of Afghanistan. Yet they will inevitably come up for discussion, and the parties might well empower a commission to amend or redraft the document. The international community has long prioritized the treatment of women as a vital litmus test of its willingness to continue to bankroll Afghanistan, something that even the Taliban quietly recognize; this might prove important leverage for donors to prevent any deal from trading these rights away. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Intra-Afghan discussions will need to broach the larger questions at the heart of the war.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, no agreement will be stable unless it meaningfully provides for the enormous population of fighters and prisoners that the war has created. The Afghan government currently holds tens of thousands of battlefield prisoners, most of them Taliban fighters, and the Taliban can reportedly mobilize up to 60,000 men. Most Afghan leaders appear inclined to release the majority of these prisoners, forgive most crimes, and help fighters find gainful employment as the price of peace. Even a magnanimous approach, however, comes with serious challenges. Disillusioned fighters could drift toward groups such as the Islamic State (or ISIS). The Taliban may resist demobilizing even under a peace agreement. Victims may bitterly oppose impunity for murderers. And whatever happens in the negotiations, Afghanistan’s poor economy will struggle to absorb tens of thousands of young men. Reintegrating these fighters into society will take years of arduous work, even if the parties agree on principles at the outset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIM HIGH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Afghan negotiators could begin to address some of the country’s most fundamental issues in their first round of talks. Alternatively, they could aim for something simpler and more immediately achievable, such as a suite of confidence-building measures or a schedule of milestones that puts off resolving core disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parties should be wary, however, of setting their sights too low. Addressing the major questions concerning Afghanistan’s future will only get harder over time. The world’s attention may move on, Afghan and international parties may become less committed to peace, and outside events may roil the country’s domestic politics. Nobody expects an immediate grand bargain, but the negotiators may be able to find a sweet spot—for instance, an agreement on the mechanics of the transition process and on a set of principles to guide future negotiations on the longer-term substantive issues. Early talks may not settle on new constitutional language, for example, but they might empower a commission to do so and give it guidance on what can or cannot be changed. Each guideline will chip away at the conflict’s central disputes at a moment—possibly fleeting—when both the government and the Taliban are willing to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ending Afghanistan’s war will require all parties to make difficult compromises. An intra-Afghan settlement is the only plausible way to achieve stability, however; neither a hasty U.S. withdrawal nor an inertial U.S. presence can bring it about. Washington must do whatever it can to help intra-Afghan negotiations succeed—most importantly by reinforcing that the departure of U.S. troops depends on the talks’ progress. This offer of a conditional U.S. withdrawal was necessary to create the current moment of opportunity, but ultimately, peace in Afghanistan depends on Afghans themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;JOHNNY WALSH is Senior Expert at the United States Institute for Peace and a former State Department senior advisor on the Afghanistan peace process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, September 5, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Johnny Walsh</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-09-05/deal-taliban-only-first-step-toward-peace</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/09/05/rtx72ibg.jpg?itok=6bFyLd0Y</image>
 <media:description>At the site of a car bombing in Kabul, August 2019 - Omar Sobhani / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>The Real Negotiations Are About to Begin</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T08:51:45-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>To Cure Ebola Will Take More Than a Pill</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/democratic-republic-congo/2019-09-04/cure-ebola-will-take-more-pill</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Two experimental drugs used to treat the Ebola virus in the Democratic Republic of the Congo are working, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/12/health/ebola-outbreak-cure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medical researchers say&lt;/a&gt;. Infected people who took the medications as part of a trial survived at rates of 66–71 percent, compared with 30 percent for those who were not vaccinated and did not receive medication. Ninety percent of patients who received treatment within the first days of showing symptoms survived. These therapies have the potential to transform Ebola from a near-certain death sentence into a difficult but survivable disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/democratic-republic-congo/2018-08-06/how-congo-beat-last-ebola-outbreak&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Congo&lt;/a&gt; especially stands to benefit. The country has experienced ten Ebola outbreaks since 1976, and its health authorities are adept at identifying and isolating infected individuals, tracing and monitoring exposure networks, and controlling the spread of the virus. But as the current outbreak in the eastern province of North Kivu has shown, no amount of medical preparedness can overcome the difficulties of fighting an outbreak under conditions of insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last 12 months, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-49521739&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more than 2,000 Ebola patients have died&lt;/a&gt; in eastern Congo, a region that has been racked by episodic instability for the last two decades. This Ebola outbreak is the second deadliest ever, eclipsed only by the one that claimed more than 11,000 lives in West Africa between 2014 and 2016. And the virus keeps on spreading: health workers confirm an average of 81 new cases each week, according to the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congo’s health ministry and the World Health Organization have led the international response to the outbreak, and their measures have proven increasingly effective. But the new drug therapies alone can’t stop this or any future epidemic. Eradicating Ebola in Congo will require building public trust among Congolese and working with community organizations in order to reach vulnerable populations and overcome governance issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A DAUNTING GROUND ZERO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Kivu sits on the far eastern edge of Congo, along the borders with Uganda and Rwanda. The region was the epicenter of two major wars that drew in many of Congo’s neighbors in the late 1990s and the early years of this century. A 2002 peace settlement officially ended those conflicts but failed to account for local disputes over land and citizenship rights in the region, so Kivu remains fraught with violence. According to researchers at New York University, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kivusecurity.nyc3.digitaloceanspaces.com/reports/28/KST%20biannual%20report%20August%2012%20%281%29.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;roughly 130 armed groups &lt;/a&gt;are currently active in North and South Kivu Provinces alone. The number and nature of these groups constantly change, but they are part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/democratic-republic-congo/2013-08-12/helping-congo-help-itself&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;insecurity&lt;/a&gt; that has continued since the wars began in 1996.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A militant group called the Allied Democratic Forces (ADF) poses an especially big problem for Ebola responders. Active in the Beni territory of North Kivu, which is the hardest hit by the outbreak, the ADF terrorizes civilians through murder and looting. Along with other armed groups such as the Mai Mai Mazembe­—a coalition of militias in the region—the ADF has helped make Beni one of the most violent places in Congo, the site of an estimated 31 percent of all civilian killings in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The violence has severely constrained the Ebola response. To contain an epidemic, health workers must be able to move quickly to identify infections, isolate patients in safe medical facilities, and trace the patients’ contacts. Responders also need to move equipment, medication, and vaccines into affected areas. All of these tasks are complicated by armed groups, which maintain roadblocks to collect bribes, attack medical facilities to loot medicines and other supplies, and kidnap people traveling through the areas they control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, insecurity has hastened the spread of the disease. According to the Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre, a Geneva-based group that tracks people who flee their homes but stay in their country, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internal-displacement.org/countries/democratic-republic-of-the-congo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more than three million&lt;/a&gt; Congolese are currently displaced as a result of conflict, and 1.8 million were newly displaced in 2018 alone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unhcr.org/en-us/dr-congo-emergency.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Another 850,000&lt;/a&gt; Congolese are refugees in other African countries, according to the United Nations. All this movement raises the risk of Ebola transmission and increases the difficulty health officials encounter in determining who may have come into contact with the virus. Should someone infected with Ebola be among those fleeing across borders to refugee camps, or to family and friends in distant cities, health authorities would have a very difficult time finding them before they exposed others to the disease. And because the symptoms take up to three weeks to present, someone unknowingly infected with the virus could easily travel, become ill, and infect others. Just such a scenario&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/20190716-dr-congo-urges-calm-after-first-case-ebola-reported-goma&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; unfolded in July&lt;/a&gt;, when a pastor who had conducted healing services in Butembo—a city with many Ebola cases—took a bus to Goma, then fell ill with the disease. Authorities have monitored his fellow bus passengers to prevent further spread of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If today’s medical responders succeed in North Kivu, they will have improved on the government’s long record of failure—a history that makes health workers’ jobs all the harder. For nearly a quarter century, the Congolese government has failed to deliver basic public services in the region. Most ordinary citizens have come to expect little besides corruption, inefficiency, and violence from public officials, so they don’t trust anything the government says, including about Ebola. As a result, Congolese don’t take symptomatic family members to health centers, hide ill people in their homes to avoid detection, and undertake traditional burial rituals without informing state authorities. All of these activities expose caregivers to infection themselves, causing the number of cases to skyrocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Suspicion of aid workers in Congo rises from a long experience of foreigners saying one thing and doing another. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congolese are equally distrustful of international actors, including aid agencies, nongovernmental organizations (NGOs), and the United Nations. Congolese concerns about what foreign aid workers are up to are easily dismissed as conspiracy-mongering (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/congo-s-ebola-response-threatened-conspiracy-theories-rumors-n994156&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fallacious rumors&lt;/a&gt; include the claim that patients are being injected with the disease). But such suspicion rises from long experience of foreigners saying one thing and doing another. The Belgians looted Congo’s natural resources under the guise of a “civilizing mission.” The CIA supported (if not actually carried out) the assassination of the country’s first post-independence prime minister. And Rwanda and Uganda have both repeatedly invaded in support of rebel movements, while the world’s largest UN peacekeeping mission has done little to actually bring peace. Given that history, one can hardly blame the Congolese for being wary of outsiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider, then, the unusual safety precautions taken by Ebola responders. Dozens of sick people enter hospitals, where foreigners keep patients out of view of families and friends, and few ever return. Families are told these people have died, but their bodies are never produced. Everything that happens is a mystery, so rumors fill the void. That groups of angry, frightened civilians have attacked Ebola treatment centers is hardly surprising under the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOWARD A REAL CURE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the obstacles and misunderstanding, there are promising signs that this epidemic can be brought under control. The new Ebola vaccine has prevented most health workers from contracting the disease from their patients. And although the Congolese government is weak, its Ebola response and vaccination programs are not. In Congo and in neighboring countries, extensive vaccination programs run by the state and NGO partners have been underway since the outbreak began. While isolated cases have made it to Goma and across the border to Uganda, health workers quickly contained them, and there have been no major outbreaks beyond northern North Kivu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very weakness of the Congolese state supplies another reason for hope. Because the government has been so dysfunctional for so long, Protestant and Catholic churches run much of the country’s public health system and manage most public hospitals and clinics. Under this system, church-run health facilities are part of the public health system, for which NGOs help supply funding and implement programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church health authorities are at the forefront of the Ebola vaccination, prevention, and treatment efforts. Their role matters because churches were among the few social institutions to survive the state’s collapse: while the government, economy, army, and just about everything else ceased to function as instruments of public good, the religious institutions survived. Almost every Congolese is a member of a church or mosque, to which congregants look for leadership and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the most of these robust religious networks, and of the high levels of trust Congolese place in them, Ebola responders should work more closely with religious leaders, especially to spread information about early Ebola symptoms and effective treatment. Ebola responders should provide regular briefings to pastors and imams and encourage them to incorporate Ebola information into weekly services. Responders should also work with religious leaders to develop alternative rituals that allow families to properly commemorate their loved ones while preventing Ebola from spreading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fa-stage-files.s3.amazonaws.com/styles/large-crop-landscape/s3/images/articles/2019/09/03/rts2mij7.jpg?itok=AR7P5zBH&quot; alt=&quot;Children look at a billboard providing information about Ebola in the eastern Democratic Republic of Congo, August 2019&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Children look at a billboard providing information about Ebola in the eastern Democratic Republic of Congo, August 2019 - Baz Ratner / Reuters&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Churches are not the only bastions of the public’s trust. Responders should enlist the help of Congolese civil society organizations and local NGOs such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.actforcongo.org/hold-drc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Goma’s HOLD-DRC&lt;/a&gt; to disseminate information, answer questions, and assuage fears. These and other reputable&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.easterncongo.org/about/publications/cbo-database&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; community-based organizations&lt;/a&gt; enjoy high levels of trust. Their representatives speak local languages and can communicate lifesaving information in culturally sensitive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local NGOs can even help Ebola responders contain the disease among migrants fleeing violence. Responders currently run health-monitoring posts along major roads and in refugee camps. These are necessary but not sufficient. Local NGOs can help find potentially infected people in urban areas that host large numbers of unregistered, displaced Congolese. Donors should finance and train leaders in these urban centers to reach out to displaced people, in the languages the migrants speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 2014–16 Ebola outbreak in West Africa, too, trust was of the essence. One simple innovation—the use of transparent isolation tent walls that allow family members to see and visit with infected family members—helped to dispel rumors and calm fears. Health workers in Congo should make the most of the lessons their colleagues learned from&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/west-africa/2015-08-18/ebolas-lessons&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; the last epidemic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trajectory in eastern Congo is positive, but the outcome will not depend only on the hope the new drugs provide. Working closely with religious institutions and community organizations, coming up with innovative solutions, and building trust within the population will ultimately allow responders to defeat the Ebola virus in eastern Congo. But given the daunting challenge responders face—an extremely insecure environment, population movements, and high levels of mistrust—it will be an uphill battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;LAURA SEAY is Assistant Professor of Government at Colby College.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, September 4, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Laura Seay</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/democratic-republic-congo/2019-09-04/cure-ebola-will-take-more-pill</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/29/rtx72ahy_bazratner.jpg?itok=1pThViFt</image>
 <media:description>A health worker in the Democratic Republic of Congo fills a syringe with the Ebola vaccine - Baz Ratner / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>What Congo Must Do to Prevent Future Outbreaks</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T14:17:32-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Plan B in Venezuela</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/venezuela/2019-09-03/plan-b-venezuela</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;From its first weeks in office, the administration of U.S. President Donald Trump has been intent on dislodging Nicolás Maduro from power in Venezuela—resorting to everything from tough talk of “military options” and indictments of senior officials to hard-hitting sanctions and multilateral diplomacy. In January, after two years of effort, Washington seemed to be close to reaching its goal. With an uncharacteristic display of careful diplomatic coordination, the United States, along with several Latin American governments and other U.S. partners, announced that it would recognize Juan Guaidó, the then-35-year-old leader of the National Assembly, as the country’s interim president. And this move, the thinking went, would surely, before long, catalyze a military or popular uprising that would drive the dictatorial Maduro from power. When Guaidó, with the support of some military figures, launched a high-stakes attempt to seize power at the end of April, it seemed that Maduro’s end might finally have arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except it didn’t. The attempt failed, and since April, Venezuela has remained stuck in a purgatorial stalemate. Maduro presides over a collapsing state but remains entrenched in Caracas. Guaidó, the country’s most popular political figure, is too powerful to jail but wields little actual authority. And the United States continues to insist on its demands, gambling that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-imposes-maximum-pressure-on-former-maduro-regime/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;maximum pressure&lt;/a&gt;”—diplomatic isolation, intensifying sanctions, and threats of military force—will eventually bring Maduro down, despite its failure so far. Meanwhile, the humanitarian catastrophe in Venezuela, where by year’s end GDP will have fallen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/17/world/americas/venezuela-economy.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;62 percent&lt;/a&gt; since 2013 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/b6459434-b531-11e9-8cb2-799a3a8cf37b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;six to eight million people&lt;/a&gt; don’t have enough to eat, goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States must now reassess its approach. Washington shouldn’t give up its sustained focus on the crisis or its stated objective of restoring democracy and constitutional order, but it does have to accept the facts on the ground and recognize that maximalist demands are unhelpful. Rather than clinging to the fading hope that pressure alone will topple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/venezuela/2019-06-24/preparing-venezuela-after-maduro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Maduro&lt;/a&gt;, Washington should reorient both its sanctions policy and its diplomatic engagement around the search for a negotiated pathway to elections. At the same time, it must reckon far more seriously with the humanitarian dimensions of Venezuela’s crisis—including the damage done by U.S. sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOUGH TALKING&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, Washington has stayed far away from negotiations—including the intermittent Norwegian-sponsored talks that began in May. The Trump administration has good reason to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/continued-u-s-support-for-democracy-in-venezuela/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;skeptical&lt;/a&gt; of talks. Dialogue has become a dirty word for many in the Venezuelan opposition as well, thanks to Maduro’s record of using negotiations to buy time, consolidate his support, and splinter his adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration has instead publicly raised pressure on Maduro with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/06/us/politics/venezuela-embargo-sanctions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new sanctions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/06/world/americas/venezuela-sanctions-bolton-maduro.html?module=inline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tough talk&lt;/a&gt; from officials such as National Security Adviser John Bolton. Recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-venezuela-politics/venezuelas-maduro-says-there-has-been-contact-with-u-s-officials-for-months-idUSKCN1VB030&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; of contact between the Trump and Maduro teams, as well as the State Department’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/28/world/americas/us-amnesty-venezuela-maduro.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pledge&lt;/a&gt; that the United States will not prosecute Maduro if he leaves power voluntarily, indicate some alternative views within the administration. But the need to sustain public hawkishness undercuts any private pragmatism. The result is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wilsoncenter.org/article/how-the-trump-administrations-venezuela-policy-just-doesnt-add&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;disjointed policy&lt;/a&gt;, with U.S. partners confused by Trump’s strategy and Guaidó surprised by some of the administration’s moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the dearth of other options, Washington should participate directly in the search for a negotiated solution, channeling its skepticism into shaping the conditions and agenda for talks rather than remaining on the sidelines. While the Norwegian-sponsored negotiations have identified the outlines of a potential deal (early presidential elections with measures to ensure a free and fair vote), without U.S. engagement, the chances the talks will succeed are slim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States should take a more hands-on approach, similar to the one it adopted for the Colombian peace talks that concluded successfully in 2016. In that case, President Barack Obama’s administration appointed an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/this-us-envoy-helped-colombia-forge-peace-his-departure-leaves-a-vacuum/2017/01/29/75ecb988-ddc2-11e6-b2cf-b67fe3285cbc_story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;envoy&lt;/a&gt; through whom the United States could protect its interests, incentivize progress, and make offers to resolve difficult issues. Venezuela has a different dynamic, but there, too, a direct link to the negotiations would demonstrate U.S. commitment to diplomacy and supply a real-time understanding of the issues at play. Trump already has an envoy for Venezuela, Elliott Abrams, but he has kept the talks at arm’s length thus far. If Abrams and his colleagues fully engaged with negotiations, they could work more effectively with like-minded Latin American and European multilateral groups to set the stage for future talks, including by forging a joint sanctions strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The United States must calibrate its sanctions policy more closely to its diplomatic agenda.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctions still have an important role to play, and they provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/venezuela/2019-01-25/venezuelan-oppositions-high-stakes-assault-maduro&quot;&gt;Guaidó&lt;/a&gt; with his best source of leverage. But the United States must calibrate its sanctions policy more closely to its diplomatic agenda. In the current negotiations, Maduro’s team has made sanctions relief one of its principal demands. The United States’ current approach has been to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-venezuela-politics-usa-bolton/u-s-might-lift-sanctions-on-venezuelan-military-who-back-guaido-bolton-idUSKCN1PV2J3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vaguely promise&lt;/a&gt; lifting sanctions against individuals who shift their loyalty to Guaidó. Instead, the Trump administration needs to communicate precisely what relief it is prepared to offer in response to which positive steps on the part of the regime. In so doing, it will need to account for the interests of potential spoilers within the regime as well as the Venezuelan military and Maduro allies such as China, Russia, and Cuba. Their interests vary widely from personal to geopolitical, but in almost all cases the United States has leverage that can be deployed most effectively by being close to the negotiating table.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For negotiations to be viable, the White House must be willing to swallow some bitter pills and even to incur the displeasure of the Guaidó coalition and Congress. Acknowledging Maduro as Venezuela’s de facto&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;leader, even if Guaidó is the country’s legitimate leader, will be particularly difficult to stomach. But if there is to be any hope that talks will lead to democratic elections, Maduro must be allowed a seat at the table and a potential role in the transition, provided his powers are sufficiently constrained. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the administration must take military action off the table, or at the very least stop invoking the threat in public. That unilateral military intervention would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/venezuela/2019-03-19/what-military-intervention-venezuela-would-look&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;risky and expensive&lt;/a&gt; is so clear that official assertions that “all options are on the table” never resonated as more than an effort to spook the Venezuelan military into abandoning Maduro. But such statements have led members of Guaidó’s coalition to overestimate their leverage and created divisions and distractions in opposition circles. By quieting speculation about potential military action, the administration would help preserve the unity of the international and Venezuelan coalitions working to restore democracy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FIRST, DO NO HARM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuela’s economic and humanitarian crisis will endure until Maduro’s regime ends and democracy is restored. But even as the United States pushes for a negotiated transition, it must work to alleviate the suffering of the Venezuelan people and those in neighboring countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scale and toll of Venezuela’s collapse has been shocking. More than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unhcr.org/en-us/news/press/2019/6/5cfa2a4a4/refugees-migrants-venezuela-top-4-million-unhcr-iom.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;four million&lt;/a&gt; Venezuelans have fled their country to date; the number could grow to eight million by the end of next year. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/EN/HRBodies/HRC/RegularSessions/Session41/Documents/A_HRC_41_18.docx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet paints a portrait of desperation: millions of Venezuelans are malnourished, and many lack medicine, electricity, water, and gasoline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration should elevate humanitarian considerations as a U.S. priority—including when it comes to the collateral impact of the maximum pressure campaign. The administration has allocated more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/apr-10-2019-united-states-provides-additional-humanitarian-aid-venezuelans-who-fled-country&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$200 million&lt;/a&gt; for humanitarian assistance, but Venezuela’s neighbors have shouldered a far greater cost by accepting millions of fleeing Venezuelans. The United States should lead by example by raising the refugee admissions cap and granting Temporary Protected Status to Venezuelans, which would allow more Venezuelans to settle in the United States and protect those already here from deportation—a step that the administration opposes but the House of Representatives approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration would then have the standing to convene a humanitarian summit alongside the UN General Assembly this month, as the Obama administration did in response to the Syria refugee crisis, in order to secure concrete commitments from governments, multilateral institutions, and the private sector, with the aim of harmonizing policy toward Venezuelan migrants among principal destination countries. Colombia needs more money for humanitarian assistance, for example, but even more than that, it needs other countries to accept more refugees rather than harden their borders, as Chile, Peru, and Ecuador have done in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;United States’ sanctions are harming ordinary Venezuelans more than Maduro and his henchmen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Washington needs to reflect on how its own policies might be worsening the plight of the Venezuelan people as Maduro clings to power. Sanctions on Venezuela’s oil sector (which traditionally accounted for &lt;a href=&quot;https://foreignpolicy.com/2018/01/12/why-more-sanctions-wont-help-venezuela/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;95 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the country’s export revenue) risk doing just this and have been met with growing concern from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/EN/NewsEvents/Pages/DisplayNews.aspx?NewsID=24788&amp;amp;LangID=E&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UN High Commissioner for Human Rights&lt;/a&gt; Bachelet and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/08/world/americas/venezuela-sanctions-maduro.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; who are not Maduro’s friends. The United States introduced sanctions on the state-owned oil firm, PDVSA, in January, on the theory that this privation would finally break Maduro’s resistance. Collateral damage to the Venezuelan people was thereby justified as a short-term cost. Needless to say that theory was flawed, and as the standoff drags on, sanctions are harming ordinary Venezuelans more than Maduro and his henchmen: in April, Venezuelan imports dropped to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/cba0fe06-9d74-11e9-9c06-a4640c9feebb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$303 million&lt;/a&gt;, eight percent of 2012 figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without question, the Maduro regime is itself responsible for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/17/world/americas/venezuela-economy.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;single largest economic collapse&lt;/a&gt; outside a war zone in at least 45 years. But U.S. actions are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/f7dd72a4-c044-11e9-b350-db00d509634e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;aggravating&lt;/a&gt; the consequences of this collapse while handing Maduro an easy scapegoat. The Trump administration might argue that economic sanctions need time to take full effect. But sanctions have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/united-states/2019-04-29/sanctions-cant-spark-regime-change&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;poor record&lt;/a&gt; of producing regime change, and the administration’s waiting game comes at a terrible human price. For Venezuelan society to resist Maduro, it must be able to eat. By one estimate, more than eight in ten Venezuelans now rely on food handouts from Maduro that are conditioned on political loyalty—hardly ripe conditions for a popular uprising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now a risk that sectoral sanctions on Venezuelan oil, gold, and other sources of revenue become an article of faith rather than a tool of foreign policy, as happened with Cuba, where a half-century embargo remains untouched despite its failure to dislodge the communist government. The Trump administration must find a way to avoid that outcome. One model is the UN’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/impact-un-oil-food-scandal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;oil-for-food&lt;/a&gt; program, which allowed Saddam Hussein’s Iraq to sell oil in exchange for food and medicine, thereby shielding civilians from the damage of economic sanctions; though the program was corruption-ridden in practice, it was theoretically sound in concept. The administration should explore a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/804b2040-39d2-11e9-b856-5404d3811663&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;similar scheme&lt;/a&gt; in Venezuela, one that would allow the United States to walk back its sectoral sanctions while channeling revenues toward humanitarian relief instead of the Maduro regime. Whether Maduro would accept such a scheme remains an open question, but it is a question he should be forced to answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PREPARE FOR THE WORST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if Washington takes all of the above precautions—if it helps steer talks and works to mitigate the humanitarian crisis—the United States must prepare for the worst-case scenario, in which Maduro clings to power for years to come or is replaced in a palace coup by a similarly minded leader.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Maduro stays, then Venezuela will continue its descent into a shelter for criminals and an exporter of chaos. The regional spillover effects—millions more refugees, supercharged transnational crime networks, outbreaks of communicable diseases, cross-border attacks by guerrilla organizations operating from Venezuelan safe havens—could destabilize parts of South America and the Caribbean basin for a decade or more. U.S. agencies should help their regional counterparts plan for the foreseeable consequences of a long-term breakdown of Venezuelan state and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should such a scenario come about, policymakers may be limited to containing the problem rather than resolving it. Few in Washington or Venezuela desire this outcome. But U.S. policymakers must reckon candidly with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/20/opinion/venezuelas-dictatorship-maduro.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;staying power&lt;/a&gt; of the Maduro regime, even while redoubling their best diplomatic efforts to dislodge it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;MICHAEL J. CAMILLERI is Director of the Peter D. Bell Rule of Law Program at the Inter-American Dialogue and a former Director for Andean Affairs at the National Security Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, September 3, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Michael J. Camilleri</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/venezuela/2019-09-03/plan-b-venezuela</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/29/rts2mijc.jpg?itok=TZfMkPCa</image>
 <media:description>A man walks in front of a sign that reads &quot;Trump unblock Venezuela&quot; in Caracas, Venezuela - Fausto Torrealba / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>Washington Must Give Up on an Ideal Strategy in Favor of an Achievable One </subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T14:18:28-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Bolsonaro Fans the Flames</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/americas/2019-08-30/bolsonaro-fans-flames</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Thousands of fires have raged over the past weeks in the Amazon, devastating parts of the rainforest and badly damaging Brazil’s global reputation. Since taking office in January, the country’s far-right president, Jair Bolsonaro, has encouraged deforestation, a policy that environmentalists around the world link to the forest fires and have loudly protested. But Bolsonaro seems to revel in his role as environmental enemy number one, responding to criticism from world leaders in the same way he reacts to his opponents at home: with provocative disdain. He taunted French President Emmanuel Macron and German Chancellor Angela Merkel, called the fires and the deforestation of parts of Brazil’s rainforest an “internal issue,” and repeated that “the Amazon belongs to Brazil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolsonaro views international concern over the fires in the Amazon as a threat to his country’s sovereignty. He and a coterie of closely allied ministers and advisers—known collectively as the “ideological faction” of the Bolsonaro government—ascribe the criticism to a globally coordinated campaign to weaken Brazil’s territorial integrity and keep it from developing economically. During the 1970s, when a military dictatorship governed Brazil, nationalists zealously promoted the notion of an international conspiracy bent on undermining the country’s sovereignty. Bolsonaro remains nostalgic for the era of the dictatorship. By striking its chords amid the environmental outcry, he assumes the role of culture warrior, fighting the “globalism” and “cultural Marxism” of international institutions and foreign-funded civil society organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolsonaro’s ideological posture led him to dig in on the forest fires, and he was further aggravated by a personal dispute with Macron. But as the fires and the opprobrium continued to rage, worried advisers convinced the president to dispatch 43,000 soldiers to the forest. Moving troops to the forest to fight the fires—a palliative measure—is unlikely to change the international perception of Brazil. Safeguarding the Amazon will require a broad reversal of Bolsonaro’s environmental agenda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the three factions in Bolsonaro’s government—his associated ideologues and members of the military—are unlikely to embrace such a reversal. These factions share the fundamental view that environmentalists may threaten Brazil’s sovereignty. The third faction, composed of liberal economists and business interests, still has an outside chance to convince Bolsonaro to adopt necessary environmental policies by appealing to Brazil’s long-term economic and foreign policy interests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE IDEOLOGUES AND THE GENERALS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forest fires occur every year in the Amazon. The year before Bolsonaro took office, from 2017 to 2018, Brazil’s Amazon forest lost nearly one billion trees. The current government is not the first to neglect the problem. Nonetheless, its contempt for the environment is particularly brazen, and this year’s deforestation will almost certainly surpass last year’s figure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolsonaro and Ricardo Salles, Brazil’s minister of the environment, do not believe in climate change. The president campaigned on promises to cut back government protections for the rainforest. He has made good on that pledge in part by slashing the budget for Ibama, Brazil’s environmental watchdog, which enforces regulations and imposes fines for illegal logging and other encroachments. The government sacked the head of the National Institute for Space Research, which publishes data on deforestation. (Scientists at the institute claim that fires this year are up 35 percent from the average of the past eight years.) And the president has fostered an atmosphere of impunity, encouraging loggers, ranchers, miners, and farmers to breach regulations and cut into the forest. Government agencies have imposed far fewer fines this year than in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“Isn’t Norway that country that kills whales up there in the North Pole?” Bolsonaro quipped.&lt;/blockquote&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Bolsonaro government has made no secret of its hostility toward environmental NGOs and international conservation efforts. Without providing evidence, Bolsonaro accused environmental NGOs of having started the fires. And the government has questioned the value of the Amazon Fund, an enormously successful conservation program financed by the Norwegian and German governments. Over the past decade, Norway has committed more than $1 billion to the fund, which supports hundreds of projects across the Amazon to reduce deforestation. NGOs play a significant role in managing the fund—an arrangement the donors consider crucial to its success. But in May, Salles demanded a reduction in the NGOs’ role—a deliberate provocation that predictably led Norway and Germany to suspend their payments. “Isn’t Norway that country that kills whales up there in the North Pole?” Bolsonaro quipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideologues in the Bolsonaro government, including the president’s powerful son Eduardo, the Foreign Minister Ernesto Araújo, and Salles, seem to welcome international ostracism. Bolsonaro thrives on controversy and conflict, and the international criticism helps strengthen the president’s narrative that powerful forces are at work to undermine him, even while it helps rally his government’s most ardent supporters around the flag. The more hostile international rhetoric becomes, the more Bolsonaro will embrace a “bunker mentality,” entrenching himself in opposition to world leaders such as Macron. The Brazilian president may not even be that bothered that his handling of the fires is threatening a major free-trade deal between Brazil and the European Union. Unlike Paulo Guedes, Bolsonaro’s economically liberal minister of the economy, the president is an economic nationalist who has favored protectionist policies all his political life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the extent that the radicalism of Bolsonaro’s ideological faction threatens the country’s economic interests, Brazil’s generals have acted as a moderating force. Vice President Hamilton Mourão, a former army general, has shouldered this duty. In the months after Bolsonaro’s election victory in October 2018, Bolsonaro and Araújo repeatedly attacked China, Brazil’s most important trading partner. Mourão worked tirelessly behind the scenes to undo the damage, traveling to Beijing to meet Chinese premier Xi Jinping in a show of goodwill. Bolsonaro proposed transferring the Brazilian embassy in Israel from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem last November. Mourão again intervened, aware that such a move could affect Brazil’s important trade ties to the Arab world. The vice president played a similar role in a recent contretemps between Bolsonaro and the president of Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental policy, however, is a different matter altogether. Those who expect the military faction to act yet again as the adult in the room and provide a check to Bolsonaro are likely to be disappointed. Mourão himself has expressed doubts about whether climate change is actually man-made. The armed forces are fully aligned with the president’s views on sovereignty and international interference. The former commander of Brazil’s army, the influential General Eduardo Villas Boas, closed ranks with Bolsonaro when he rejected international criticism as a “direct attack on Brazilian sovereignty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIBERALS TO THE RESCUE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With both the ideological and military factions of the government shrugging off international pressure, the government’s third faction, the neoliberals, has begun to mobilize against the president’s environmental policies, reaching out to agribusiness and civil society. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The liberal faction is led by Brazil’s minister of agriculture, Tereza Cristina, and by Guedes, and it includes many skilled technocrats in the ministry of the economy. Both worry that Bolsonaro’s posture on the forest fires will disturb trade negotiations and undercut efforts to liberalize and restart Brazil’s sluggish economy. Brazilian diplomats privately concede that the furor is likely to delay or even prevent the country’s long-sought accession to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development. And the Europeans could still refuse to ratify the EU-Mercosur trade deal, a pact that is estimated to add nearly $90 billion to Brazil’s economy over the next 15 years, and which Bolsonaro counts as one of his biggest foreign policy achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The neoliberals have begun to mobilize against the president’s environmental policies.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stakes are not lost on Brazil’s business leaders, particularly in agribusiness, which accounts for more than 20 percent of the country’s GDP. The European Union currently buys $5 billion worth of Brazilian soy per year. Marcello Brito, head of the powerful Brazilian Agribusiness Association, recently warned that “it is only a matter of time” before the fires prompt boycotts of Brazilian products. In such a scenario, Brito noted, Brazil would struggle enormously to “regain confidence” abroad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the contest among the three factions that make up Brazil’s government, the liberal pro-business faction holds one trump card, and that is the parlous state of Brazil’s underperforming economy and the swelling ranks of its 13 million unemployed. Unless he can manage a return to significant economic growth, Bolsonaro will not likely see his low approval ratings recover. His government has bowed to pressure from the business sector before. As president-elect in the fall of 2018, Bolsonaro expressed willingness to withdraw from the Paris agreement on climate change. Ambassadors from European Union member states coordinated a pressure campaign, meeting one-on-one with Brazilian congressmen representing agribusiness. The European diplomats told the lawmakers that if Brazil left the Paris agreement, consumers across Europe would boycott Brazilian products. Days later, Salles, the environment minister, announced Brazil would not abandon the commitments it made in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet European pressure may not make much of an impression on Brazil’s domestic policy. Unlike the big agricultural associations, Brazil’s small farmers continue to support Bolsonaro’s loosening of environmental protections. With less exposure to the international market, these farmers tend to prefer lax environmental rules. They are often actively involved in deforestation and disinterested in, or unaware of, its global repercussions. And Brazil will not be without trading partners in case of a European boycott: China buys 80 percent of Brazil’s soy exports, and this relationship has proved unresponsive to Bolsonaro’s shredding of environmental protections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolsonaro certainly faces little pressure from the White House. At the G-7 meeting in Biarritz this month, U.S. President Donald Trump, himself a climate skeptic, dismissed the Amazon conflagration as a “niche issue.” Even European leaders are not united in their approach. Macron has adopted an aggressive strategy, accusing the Brazilian president of lying and insisting that he won’t ratify the EU-Mercosur deal under current circumstances. German Chancellor Angela Merkel disagrees, arguing that refusing to ratify the trade deal will not prevent “a single hectare” from being illegally logged in Brazil’s rainforest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending troops to the Amazon to contain the fires is laudable but insufficient. To really protect the rainforest and take Brazil’s environmental responsibilities seriously, Bolsonaro must reverse his government’s systematic weakening of its environmental protection agency. He must explicitly recognize that climate change is real. And he should accept that NGOs make positive contributions in combatting deforestation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such an about-face is highly unlikely. Bolsonaro’s ideological anti-environmental views are deeply intertwined with his entire political project. Economic liberals can raise the specter of a scrapped trade deal with the European Union, consumer boycotts, and denial of OECD membership—but such pragmatic concerns may not sway a president so committed to defiance, no matter the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;OLIVER STUENKEL is an Associate Professor of International Relations at the Getulio Vargas Foundation, Brazil. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, August 30, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Oliver Stuenkel</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/americas/2019-08-30/bolsonaro-fans-flames</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/29/rts2o74l.jpg?itok=_XoU19Rb</image>
 <media:description>Bolsonaro in Brasilia, August 2019 - Adriano Machado / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>Brazil’s Government Still Has One Faction That Can Douse Them</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-03T10:36:14-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Good Riddance to the INF Treaty</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-29/good-riddance-inf-treaty</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;In early August, the United States formally withdrew from the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty, a landmark 1987 arms control accord with Russia. Just two weeks later, on a small island off the Californian coast, the Pentagon tested a land-based missile once banned under the agreement. The demise of the INF Treaty is now official, on paper as on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The treaty’s collapse was a long time coming. An agreement cannot work if only one party honors it, and the INF Treaty’s sole cosignatory, Moscow, had been flouting its rules for years. During his presidency, Barack Obama considered withdrawing from the INF for precisely the same reason that helped drive President Donald Trump’s decision. Still, to many observers, the decision to ditch the treaty is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/2019-03-04/mourning-inf-treaty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;misguided and dangerous&lt;/a&gt;. The Trump administration, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/russian-federation/2019-08-06/return-doomsday&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;they argue&lt;/a&gt;, is dismantling guardrails that were erected to keep tensions from escalating into a destabilizing arms race. At a time when several elements of the global arms control architecture are fraying, this latest casualty could only make matters worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that line of criticism misses the point. If unilateral U.S. adherence to the treaty was futile in the face of repeated Russian transgressions, it had become outright dangerous in the face of a much more potent adversary—China. During the INF Treaty’s 32-year lifespan, China developed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andrewerickson.com/2018/12/the-china-anti-ship-ballistic-missile-asbm-bookshelf/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;world’s foremost conventional missile force&lt;/a&gt;, brimming with the very weapons that the treaty prohibited the United States from developing: ground-launched cruise and ballistic missiles with a range of 500 to 5,500 kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, China uses that missile arsenal to threaten the United States and its allies and partners throughout East Asia. Exiting the INF Treaty is no panacea, but it opens much-needed possibilities for Washington to reset the military balance with Beijing in its favor. Washington should use this opportunity to develop and deploy its own missiles to counter the Chinese threat—or risk being steamrolled in a future confrontation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CHINA PULLS AHEAD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The INF Treaty, with its narrow focus on the United States and Russia, always acted as a straightjacket for U.S. strategy in Asia. In theory, the United States could have pushed for China to join the treaty—but China wouldn’t, and it still won’t. Beijing derives great benefit from its large land-based missile force and has made clear that it won’t accede to any substantive arms control agreements for the foreseeable future. At an emergency session of the U.N. Security Council on August 22, for instance, China’s permanent representative to the United Nations, Zhang Jun, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.china-un.org/eng/hyyfy/t1691256.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enjoined&lt;/a&gt; Washington to “exercise restraint and earnestly preserve the existing arms control regime” while insisting that China’s own missiles pose “no threat to any country.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The INF Treaty, with its narrow focus on the United States and Russia, always acted as a straightjacket for U.S. strategy in Asia.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last three decades, China has made meteoric military progress by pursuing technologies that place opponents on the wrong side of physics. Ballistic missiles, which travel at multiple times the speed of sound and are therefore extremely difficult to intercept, have been the cornerstone of that effort. China can develop and deploy these weapons far more cheaply and effectively than the United States can defend against them, making any future conflict with China an extremely expensive and risky undertaking. All in all, Beijing “controls the largest and most diverse missile force in the world, with an inventory of more than 2,000 ballistic and cruise missiles,” Admiral Harry Harris, then the commander of the U.S. Pacific Command, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armed-services.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Harris_04-27-17.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;testified&lt;/a&gt; in 2017. According to Harris, some 95 percent of those missiles would have been prohibited by the INF Treaty, had China been a signatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beijing has benefitted from other forms of American myopia as well. Arms control debates tend to focus on nuclear weapons, of which China has far fewer than Russia or the United States. But China’s inventory of conventional missiles exceeds its nuclear inventory by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Chinese-Aerospace-Power-Evolving-Maritime/dp/1591142415&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a ratio of at least 7:1&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier this summer, Beijing fired six anti-ship ballistic missiles into contested waters in the South China Sea, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://aspensecurityforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Military-Competition-with-China-Maintaining-Americas-Edge.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;signal of assertiveness&lt;/a&gt; to its neighbors, Washington, and the world at large. It now fields several dozen such “carrier killer” missiles, named for their potential ability to destroy warships or aircraft carriers far from Chinese shores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of China’s missiles are land-based, rather than deployed on aircraft, ships, or submarines. That spells additional trouble for the United States. Large missiles of the type covered by the INF are substantially easier and cheaper to develop and operate on land than at sea or in the skies. They are also difficult to find and neutralize prior to their launch. This was true of Saddam Hussein’s Scud missiles during the first Gulf War, which the U.S. military struggled to locate even in exposed desert; it is even truer of China’s arsenal of cruise and ballistic missiles, which is hidden in varied terrains and extensive underground facilities, and made even more elusive by road-mobile launchers and a network of secure fiber optic cables built to ensure communication with the launch brigades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from its disruptive cybertechnologies, China’s missile-centric military buildup may be the single biggest factor eroding U.S. power and influence in Asia. In a moment of crisis, this destructive arsenal could embolden Beijing to pursue its oft-invoked “core interests”—including its disputed claim to sovereignty over Taiwan—by trying to establish a fait accompli, forcing Washington and its regional allies to cave before the fighting even begins. U.S. air bases and aircraft carriers are technologically sophisticated compared to China’s, but they are vulnerable to Chinese missile forces. As a result, Washington should take a page out of Beijing’s own post–Cold War playbook and build a deterrent based on land-based missiles. Luckily, the death of the INF Treaty offers the perfect opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HOW TO CATCH UP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unshackled from the INF Treaty, what can the United States do to level the playing field? To begin with, it can once again develop and test ground-launched medium- and intermediate-range missiles. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/english/2019-08/20/c_138321576.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Testing has begun&lt;/a&gt; on a ground-launched variant of the &lt;em&gt;Tomahawk&lt;/em&gt;, allowing deployment within approximately 18 months. A mobile, ground-launched intermediate-range ballistic missile (IRBM) with a range of 3,000 to 4,000 kilometers will eventually follow but will likely take several years to develop, because unlike the &lt;em&gt;Tomahawk &lt;/em&gt;the IRBM lacks a post–Cold War analog on which to base new missiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;China’s missiles may be the single biggest factor eroding U.S. power and influence in Asia.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As these new missiles become available, the United States should deploy them in the Asia-Pacific. For now, the most realistic and promising location is the U.S. overseas territory of Guam. Other U.S. territories in the Pacific, Australia, Japan, the Philippines, and South Korea are also potential locations. To be sure, small islands such as Guam have only limited concealing terrain, while foreign governments may face popular opposition to hosting U.S. missiles. But the winds of public opinion could shift quickly, especially if China’s military capabilities and regional ambitions continue to expand. And if peacetime politics preclude a permanent deployment in these countries, the United States can still pursue agreements that would allow it to rapidly deploy missiles for a limited period in times of crisis. (The recent deployment of mobile artillery rocket systems to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stripes.com/news/highly-mobile-rocket-systems-to-stay-in-australia-after-talisman-sabre-ends-1.589829&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt; for extended exercises suggests that such cooperation can work.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. withdrawal from the INF Treaty doesn’t close the door on future arms control initiatives. On the contrary, it puts new possibilities on the table: Russia remains free to work with the United States on nonproliferation, including in the emerging realms of hypersonic and undersea nuclear weapons, and on Moscow’s uniquely hazardous nuclear-powered cruise missile program, none of which is currently governed by any agreement. For the time being at least, Chinese leaders &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/english/2019-08/02/c_138279313.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;remain vocally opposed&lt;/a&gt; to any IRBM development by the United States but unwilling to make any concessions when it comes to their own, much bigger conventional stockpile. If the Chinese eventually come to the arms control negotiating table, it will be because Washington pursued new capabilities, not because it unilaterally tied its hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;ANDREW S. ERICKSON is Visiting Scholar at Harvard’s Fairbank Center for Chinese Studies and a Professor of Strategy at the Naval War College. He is the author of the book &lt;em&gt;Chinese Anti-Ship Ballistic Missile (ASBM) Development: Drivers, Trajectories and Strategic Implications.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, August 29, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Andrew S. Erickson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-29/good-riddance-inf-treaty</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/29/rtx1qvvj_0.jpg?itok=X5nLEgfY</image>
 <media:description>Chinese ballistic missiles at a military parade in Beijing, September 2015 - Andy Wong / REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>Washington Shouldn’t Tie Its Own Hands in Asia</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-02T08:17:15-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>How Not to Fight a Currency War </title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-28/how-not-fight-currency-war</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, the United States officially branded China a currency manipulator. Trade hawks have long argued that Washington should call out Beijing for holding down the value of its currency in order to unfairly boost its exports. But ironically, U.S. President Donald Trump picked a time when China wasn’t actually suppressing the yuan to formally brand it a manipulator. Although it has certainly manipulated its currency in the past, China stopped doing so in 2014. Yet Trump, upset by the yuan’s depreciation during the first week of August and frustrated by a lack of progress in U.S.-Chinese trade talks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/trump-pressured-mnuchin-to-label-china-currency-manipulator-a-move-he-had-previously-resisted/2019/08/15/b487bb2e-bf84-11e9-a5c6-1e74f7ec4a93_story.html&quot;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; pressed Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin to make the designation over Mnuchin’s own objections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The designation is largely symbolic. Under the legislation cited by the U.S. Treasury Department, the penalty will be a year of negotiations between the United States and China, either directly or through the International Monetary Fund (IMF). In fact, the only way that the Treasury was able to designate China was through an expansive reading of the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988, whose criteria for manipulation include any action in the foreign exchange market aimed at “gaining an unfair advantage in international trade.” China doesn’t meet the more technical definition of manipulation set forth in the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015, which considers a country’s bilateral trade balance with the United States, whether it is a net lender to the rest of the world, and the extent of its intervention in the foreign exchange market. Both laws are currently on the books, and some aspects of the 1988 law actually might be better suited to addressing real cases of manipulation, but Trump’s use of the earlier law to designate China was nothing more than cheap theater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say the U.S. president didn’t highlight a real problem: with two flawed laws defining currency manipulation on the books, the United States lacks both adequate criteria for identifying currency manipulation and effective tools for responding to it. Unfortunately, branding China a manipulator at a time when it is not actually manipulating its currency will only make it harder to take a tough line against real manipulation in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once a Manipulator, Not Always a Manipulator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currency manipulation occurs when a country that runs a large trade surplus intervenes in the foreign exchange market with the aim of artificially depressing the value of its currency and making its exports cheaper on the global market. Although standard macroeconomic policies, such as cutting interest rates or buying domestic financial assets, can affect exchange rates, manipulation—correctly defined—is conceptually different. Whereas the aim of the former policies is to ease domestic financial conditions, the purpose of manipulation is simply to weaken a currency or to keep it from rising when it should. Governments typically accomplish this by purchasing foreign currencies and selling their own, artificially decreasing the demand for the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine manipulation can sometimes be difficult to identify, as countries may have legitimate, prudential reasons for intervening in the foreign exchange market. When a country receives large financial inflows, for example, it may wish to build up foreign exchange reserves in case those financial inflows reverse. Heavily indebted countries that run trade deficits also need to hold foreign exchange reserves to limit the risk of a crisis. But if the intervention is done by a country with a large trade surplus, then it is probably manipulation—a policy directed primarily at keeping the country’s trade surplus high rather than managing its domestic economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China began manipulating its currency roughly 15 years ago, several years after its 2001 entry into the World Trade Organization provided a massive jolt to its economy. Under normal circumstances, the rapid growth that followed would have caused the value of the yuan to increase. Yet Beijing, which was determined to keep its exports cheap, refused to let its currency rise against the dollar, buying up foreign exchange reserves to artificially deflate the value of the yuan. China’s manipulation during this period was one reason for the so-called China shock—the rapid fall, in the first decade of the current century, in manufacturing employment in U.S. and European regions that compete most directly with China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;U.S. currency policy effectively amounts to going after the wrong targets with a worthless weapon.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet China stopped manipulating its currency in the second half of 2014, when the dollar strengthened significantly as a result of the Federal Reserve’s decision to start raising interest rates and the European Central Bank’s decision to begin quantitative easing. At the time, the yuan was tightly linked to the dollar, so the dollar’s rise pulled the yuan’s value up against many of China’s trading partners, putting additional stress on its weakening economy. Amid the resulting market uncertainty, many Chinese savers started to worry that the yuan might depreciate and sought to move their funds out of China. As a result, Beijing no longer needed to buy large sums of dollars in the foreign exchange market to keep the yuan from rising. On the contrary, it at times had to sell dollars (and buy yuan) to keep the yuan from falling in value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beijing still doesn’t allow its currency to float freely—the Chinese central bank manages the market value of the yuan through means other than foreign exchange purchases, for instance by setting the center point for the yuan’s daily trading range. But today it is using these tools to keep the yuan from falling even faster than it has in recent weeks. The yuan easily could be between three and five percent weaker if China were not managing its value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous U.S. administrations made a political decision not to designate China a currency manipulator. Because the relevant legislation did not specify any real sanction for currency manipulation, top officials in the George W. Bush and Obama administrations argued that the designation would amount to name-calling without genuine consequences. They also worried that it would lead Congress to take matters into its own hands and impose sweeping tariffs on China, undermining what was believed to be the United States’ broader interest in integrating Beijing into the world economy. The Trump administration’s decision to designate China was equally political: Trump didn’t like that the yuan had depreciated against the dollar, which he feared would harm U.S. exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong Targets, Worthless Weapons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are legitimate reasons for the United States to be concerned about currency manipulation: currency manipulators effectively make it harder for their trading partners to grow their economies, especially under economic conditions such as the present, marked by weak demand, too much saving, and low interest rates. But a serious policy needs to be based on a well-defined process that sets out clear criteria for assessing a country’s actions in the foreign exchange market. The goal should be to deter countries from manipulating and name them only if they ignore clear warnings. That’s quite different from Trump designating China out of frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better set of criteria for designating currency manipulators would take as a starting point a different portion of the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 than the “unfair advantage” criterion Trump has seized on: a portion that emphasizes actions that “impede effective balance of payments adjustment”—that is, policies designed to preserve a large trade surplus. It would then look not at a country’s bilateral trade balance with the United States, as the 2015 law does, but at the country’s overall trade balance and its direct activity in the foreign exchange market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world of global value chains, a country’s trading balance with the United States isn’t a good guide to whether it’s manipulating its currency. Countries such as Singapore and Taiwan, for instance, have a history of unfair currency policies. But because they export high-end electronic components to China and Vietnam for final assembly rather than selling directly to the United States, the current set of ill-defined standards lets them off the hook. Washington should also more rigorously assess other countries’ actions in the foreign exchange market. Currently, it looks narrowly at the actions of a country’s central bank. It should expand this assessment to include an evaluation of whether a country’s state-owned banks and investment funds are helping to weaken its currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basing any claim of manipulation on a clear definition is especially important if a finding of manipulation is to be paired with real penalties. Right now, it isn’t. The 1988 law requires nothing more than a year of negotiations, and although the 2015 law calls for some sanctions, such as enhanced IMF surveillance or the loss of risk insurance through the U.S. Overseas Private Investment Corporation, these are largely pinpricks. The right penalty would be counterintervention by the United States—purchasing the currency of the manipulating country in order to push its value back up. Washington already has the legal authority to do this via the Treasury Department’s Exchange Stabilization Fund, a reserve fund authorized to deal in foreign exchange. But right now the fund has only around $100 billion in assets—enough for a currency war with a small power but not a major one such as China. Congress could appropriate more money for the fund in order to establish a more effective deterrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s decision to brand China a currency manipulator at a time when it doesn’t meet any sensible definition of manipulation was a mistake, even if the designation itself has few legal consequences. But it highlights how U.S. currency policy effectively amounts to going after the wrong targets with a worthless weapon. A better policy would make sure the United States not only names the right targets—those that are actively buying large amounts of foreign exchange in the market to hold their currencies down—but ensures there are real penalties for offending countries if they don’t change their behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;BRAD W. SETSER is Steven A. Tananbaum Senior Fellow for International Economics at the Council on Foreign Relations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, August 28, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Brad W. Setser</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-28/how-not-fight-currency-war</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/28/china_currency.jpg?itok=sfT-8q1Q</image>
 <media:description>A Chinese yuan note as seen in May 2017 - Thomas White/REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>Branding China a “Currency Manipulator” Will Only Hurt the United States</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-08-30T08:46:44-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>China’s Long March to Technological Supremacy</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-27/chinas-long-march-technological-supremacy</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Until recently, American perceptions of Chinese technology tended to be either hopeful or dismissive. On the hopeful side, the information revolution was taken as a sure drive of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2018-02-13/china-reckoning&quot;&gt;greater freedom&lt;/a&gt;. “Imagine if the Internet took hold in China,” George W. Bush said in a presidential debate in 1999. “Imagine how freedom would spread.” Some observers noted considerable theft and imitation of U.S. technology firms, but Chinese technology was generally thought to represent little or no competitive threat, with analysts explaining—as a 2014 &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt; headline put it—“why China can’t innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But China has quickly moved &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2018-08-13/when-china-rules-web&quot;&gt;up the value chain&lt;/a&gt;, creating world-class industries in everything from 5G and artificial intelligence to biotechnology and quantum computing. Some experts now believe that China could unseat the United States as the world’s leading technological force. And many U.S. policymakers view that prospect as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-07-18/how-confront-advancing-threat-china&quot;&gt;existential threat&lt;/a&gt; to U.S. economic and military power. “Very dangerous,” President Donald Trump said recently when talking about the Chinese telecommunications company Huawei; National Security Adviser John Bolton has warned of a “Manchurian chip.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet if China’s rapid technological advance came as a shock to most observers in the United States, for Chinese leaders it reflects a drive that dates to the origins of the People’s Republic. President Xi Jinping has described a formidable objective for Chinese tech: “catch up and surpass.” But that ambition, abbreviated as &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt; in Chinese, has long been one of the Chinese Communist Party’s defining goals; it remains the essential framework for understanding China’s ambition to become a technological superpower today, bringing together the legacies of Marxism, Maoism, and the tortuous pursuit of modernization by the Chinese Communist Party (CCP). In the minds of China’s leaders, from Mao Zedong to Xi Jinping, technological progress is not only a means to economic and military prowess but also an ideological end in itself—offering final proof of China’s restoration as a great power after decades of struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“CATCH UP AND SURPASS”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before Donald Trump and Xi Jinping began their trade war, the CCP’s historical fixation on advanced technology emerged from a combination of nostalgia for China’s lost imperial glory and awe for Soviet modernization. Mao, like other Chinese revolutionaries and reformers, blamed the country’s having fallen behind partly on its inability to keep up with international technological advancements. And he watched as leaders in Moscow carved their own path to technological progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, Mao’s China received extensive technological and technical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uncpress.org/book/9781469629834/the-sino-soviet-alliance/&quot;&gt;assistance&lt;/a&gt; from the Soviet “elder brother.” In 1957, Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev declared that his goal was to “catch up and surpass the United States.” Mao took the idea and made it his own, putting the Chinese variant of Khrushchev’s goal—&lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt;—at the heart of CCP ambitions. He envisioned the socialist world’s “overwhelming superiority” in science and technology and came to see technological strength as central to economic, ideological, and geopolitical power—the view of catch up and surpass that CCP leaders continue to hold today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese adaptation of catch up and surpass quickly turned fevered and utopian. Mao, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/10.1162/JCWS_a_00430&quot;&gt;impatient&lt;/a&gt; to develop faster than the overbearing Soviet Union, announced in early 1958 that China would take a Great Leap Forward, in which “politics and technology must be unified.” The Great Leap Forward—a massive campaign to rapidly industrialize and collectivize the country—ended in a catastrophic famine that killed tens of millions of people. Yet even then, the CCP did not abandon &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt;. Continued concerns about China’s military backwardness, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=3946&quot;&gt;Evan Feigenbaum&lt;/a&gt; has written, motivated repeated pushes for technological advancement. In 1975, Premier Zhou Enlai introduced the concept of the Four Modernizations: modernizing “agriculture, industry, national defense, and S &amp;amp; T . . . to the front ranks of the world” by the year 2000. And when Zhou and Mao died in 1976, their successors, Hua Guofeng and Deng Xiaoping, attempted “a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41262805&quot;&gt;new leap forward&lt;/a&gt;,” aiming to help China “catch up” by importing more than $15 billion worth of advanced technology from abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;China’s single-minded focus on ganchao explains the intensity and persistence of its theft of trade secrets.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this new leap also foundered, due to soaring debts and sloppy decision-making, Deng took a new approach to &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt;, this time relying on market reform, industrial policy, and economic opening. The CCP rehabilitated those who had been purged during the Cultural Revolution, increased investment in S &amp;amp; T research and training, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Unlikely-Partners-Chinese-Reformers-Economists/dp/0674971132/ref=sr_1_fkmr0_1&quot;&gt;sent delegations abroad&lt;/a&gt; to bring new ideas and technologies back to China, and encouraged foreign firms to set up shop in China and share sophisticated equipment and know-how. The rise of information technologies became a particular fixation of the Chinese leadership in the 1980s. In 1983, Premier Zhao Ziyang gave a speech on the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-asian-studies/article/futurists-of-beijing-alvin-toffler-zhao-ziyang-and-chinas-new-technological-revolution-19791991/9C3A0A2BA1E1FEE714548E47FA351758&quot;&gt;global New Technological Revolution&lt;/a&gt;,” invoking the need to “catch up and surpass” and citing the writings of American futurist Alvin Toffler, whose &lt;em&gt;The Third Wave &lt;/em&gt;predicted the rise of a new Information Age. Zhao and Deng sought “ ‘leap-frog’ development in key high-tech fields” such as information technology, automation, and bioengineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the marketizing economy, newly emergent private companies also served the national goal to “catch up and surpass.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinas-fearsome-dragons-1490828012&quot;&gt;Liu Chuanzhi&lt;/a&gt;, an engineer at the state-run Chinese Academy of Sciences, started a side business that grew into Lenovo, one of the world’s largest makers of personal computers. Ren Zhengfei, formerly an official in the People Liberation Army’s engineering corps, began importing and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/silicon-valley-helped-build-huawei-washington-could-dismantle-it-1544358603?mod=article_inline&quot;&gt;reverse-engineering&lt;/a&gt; foreign &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-huawei-took-over-the-world-11545735603&quot;&gt;network hardware and electronics&lt;/a&gt;, establishing &lt;a href=&quot;https://csis-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/publication/130215_competitiveness_Huawei_casestudy_Web.pdf&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt; in 1987.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1990s and 2000s, the pursuit of advanced technology involved several strategies of varying degrees of legality and publicity. Fostering the private sector remained a crucial part of the CCP’s strategy; Huawei especially won &lt;a href=&quot;https://csis-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/publication/130215_competitiveness_Huawei_casestudy_Web.pdf&quot;&gt;high-profile endorsements&lt;/a&gt; from senior Chinese leaders and tens of billions in loans from state banks, becoming a national champion as it expanded overseas and partnered with foreign companies. Information technology firms boomed, but the CCP assiduously managed the perceived political and cultural risks that accompanied the rise of the Internet. While building up the Great Firewall, China’s rulers also took advantage of the more open networks in developed countries: aggressively recruiting overseas Chinese experts to return to the PRC, obtaining foreign intellectual property by mandating the transfer of technical know-how in joint ventures, and engaging in industrial espionage targeted at high-value technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SILICON MARXISM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, shortly after being appointed CCP general secretary, Xi laid out his vision for China’s future in a series of remarks centered around the goal of national rejuvenation—regaining wealth, power, and glory for China. Alongside the problems of corruption, pollution, debt, and military competition, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/11/world/asia/xi-jinping-china-national-security.html&quot;&gt;worried openly&lt;/a&gt; about the lagging state of Chinese technology. Advanced technology had been key to the West’s “sway over the world in modern times”; Beijing would need an “asymmetrical strategy” to “catch up and surpass,” he said, explicitly invoking this decades-old CCP ambition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That long-standing view, reflecting a single-minded focus on &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt;, explains the intensity and persistence of Chinese theft of trade secrets, involving both conventional spycraft and cybercrime—what former National Security Agency Director Keith Alexander called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOFk44yy6IQ&quot;&gt;the greatest transfer of wealth&lt;/a&gt; in history.” It has been reinforced by a belief that China’s thefts were part of rectifying imperialist misdeeds by the Western countries as well as the linkage of technological advances to the ideology and identity of the CCP. It also reflects a paradox in the CCP’s relationship to technology: pursuing an ultimate state of self-reliance has relied above all on foreign technology and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Trump came into office, China’s rulers could see that their focus on &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt; was bearing fruit. Barring a major crisis, China will become the world’s largest economy by gross domestic product well before the hundredth anniversary of the People’s Republic’s founding, in 2049. Its rulers, accordingly, are already shifting from “catching up” to “surpassing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;An all-out rivalry between the world’s two technology leaders would be immensely costly, disruptive, and destructive.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xi argues that indigenous technological innovation is necessary to surpass the West, even if copying has been mostly sufficient to catch up. He &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/english/2018-05/29/c_137213175.htm&quot;&gt;calls innovation&lt;/a&gt; “the primary driving force of development,” giving a Silicon Valley–friendly gloss to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thechinastory.org/cot/jiang-shigong-on-philosophy-and-history-interpreting-the-xi-jinping-era-through-xis-report-to-the-nineteenth-national-congress-of-the-ccp/&quot;&gt;Marxist idea&lt;/a&gt; of historical “driving forces.” Working closely with private companies and universities, the CCP has positioned fields such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/newsletters/axios-future-831da177-9181-4977-8664-91886b8df875.html?chunk=0&amp;amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=newsletter_axioschina&amp;amp;stream=top#story0&quot;&gt;chipmaking&lt;/a&gt;, bioengineering, telecommunications, and artificial intelligence (AI) as test cases of whether China can “surpass” the United States. A state-supported flood of discounted capital, world-class researchers, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/blog/civil-military-fusion-missing-link-between-chinas-technological-and-military-rise&quot;&gt;civil-military fusion&lt;/a&gt;,” and less constraining norms give Chinese labs an edge. In the race to develop next-generation wireless service, 5G, Huawei is leading the pack, with one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-huawei-took-over-the-world-11545735603&quot;&gt;biggest R&amp;amp;D budgets&lt;/a&gt; of any tech company and revenues &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/huawei-long-seen-as-spy-threat-rolled-over-u-s-road-bumps-1515453829?mod=article_inline&quot;&gt;roughly equal to&lt;/a&gt; telecom competitors Nokia and Ericsson combined. And when it comes to the data powering AI, according to a report from the think tank &lt;a href=&quot;https://macropolo.org/ai-data-us-china/&quot;&gt;MacroPolo&lt;/a&gt;, China may benefit from having fewer constraints on experimenting with new systems. (The Uighurs have experienced what this is leading to in the chilling techno-authoritarian model implemented in Xinjiang.) Because the CCP already engages in large-scale surveillance and limits personal freedoms, innovations in big-data systems for smart cities and social credit point in a startlingly dystopian direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Xi, innovation is good for both maintaining social control and growing national power. His &lt;a href=&quot;https://supchina.com/2018/06/28/made-in-china-2025/&quot;&gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates the breadth of Beijing’s ambitions. Made in China 2025 aims to bolster Chinese firms and ensure that they control the domestic market in advanced technologies such as robotics, new-energy vehicles, medical devices, quantum computing, and AI. One Chinese official told &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/china-drops-a-policy-the-u-s-dislikes-at-least-in-name-11551795370&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that the plan has undergone cosmetic changes “because the Americans don’t like it.” But it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merics.org/en/papers-on-china/evolving-made-in-china-2025&quot;&gt;endures in substance&lt;/a&gt;, and other senior officials insist that the CCP “will never give an inch” on this scheme’s broader goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top-down, CCP-led technological innovation brings its share of challenges. Many observers correctly cite the risks of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/2189046/chinas-tech-strategy-all-talk-no-action-and-waste-taxpayers&quot;&gt;misguided government-steered investment&lt;/a&gt;, which has led to waste and massive oversupply, or the challenges of supporting small entrepreneurs and researchers without heavy-handed interference. But the record of the past several decades shows that CCP leaders will, in their pursuit of technological advancement, display persistence and ingenuity in responding to those obstacles. China’s leadership has certainly been prone to exaggerating its achievements throughout a long history marked by leaps, rushes, and “asymmetric steps”—but they also have a record of doing whatever it takes to make the hype real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A RACE AGAINST TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of surpassing other countries technologically does not mean that China’s rulers seek global military supremacy. But even in best-case scenarios, China’s transition from catching up to surpassing will be destabilizing, as other countries confront Chinese ambitions for greater prosperity and security and feel their relative power decrease. And for China, building 5G networks for other countries and making AI breakthroughs clearly advance CCP aims far beyond narrowly construed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-06-19/why-blacklisting-huawei-could-backfire&quot;&gt;self-reliance&lt;/a&gt;. Even if firms such as Huawei and ZTE are not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lawfareblog.com/huawei-and-managing-5g-risk&quot;&gt;incontrovertibly compromised&lt;/a&gt; by the state, their work clearly serves CCP interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology will remain at the heart of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/competition-with-china-without-catastrophe&quot;&gt;U.S.-Chinese tensions&lt;/a&gt; well beyond the end of the current trade war. Technology, to the CCP, is power in practice—it is historical change in material form. The roots of “catch up and surpass” demonstrates that the CCP’s approach to technology is far more deeply entrenched than many analysts realize. If China’s rulers feel their technological rise is under threat, they are likely to react more forcefully and uncompromisingly than policymakers may expect—as the Chinese response to Washington’s effort to block Huawei’s global 5G dominance has demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An all-out rivalry between the world’s two technology leaders would be immensely costly, disruptive, and destructive. Instead, policymakers should focus on establishing and enforcing new rules for the race already underway, so that competition can occur fairly and be at least somewhat bounded. Within the United States, that will require scrutinizing Chinese investments and acquisitions of U.S. firms, well beyond the traditional purview of the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, as well as the footprint of both Chinese firms in the United States (such as Baidu’s AI lab &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizjournals.com/sanjose/news/2017/10/04/baidu-expands-its-footprint-in-silicon-valley-with.html&quot;&gt;in Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt;) and U.S. firms in China (such as Google’s AI lab &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/google-ai-china-center/&quot;&gt;in Beijing&lt;/a&gt;). In addition, Washington should seek to begin negotiations with China as soon as possible to explore common rules for emerging technologies. Such agreements were possible with the Soviet Union during the Cold War. Today, they can be effective again if they are based on deep understanding of the technologies under discussion and the importance of tech to both countries’ conceptions of national power. For the U.S. government, that may require creating or improve policymaking institutions, such as upgrading the Office of Science and Technology Policy (which currently runs the National Science and Technology Council) into a new National Emerging Technology Council. The National Emerging Technology Council would serve as a consistent, high-level body, overlapping the National Security Council and the National Economic Council, to coordinate more effectively across the whole of government and bring empowered expertise to bear on both domestic policymaking and international negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government’s response should not be premised on the notion, evidently in vogue in both Washington and Beijing, that all scientific and technological activity is a zero-sum competition between states. The history of &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt; suggests that so-called technological decoupling between China and the United States will continue in areas where it is most difficult to distinguish between commercial and military applications. But unwinding interdependence carries significant costs, and so U.S. policymakers should attempt to draw distinctions between sectors in China that feature strong private-sector leadership and those dominated by the state—not all “Chinese” technology is the same. Research institutions and private companies will also need much more help evaluating potential research cooperation with Chinese counterparts, to guard against problematic partnerships while preserving the great value of international exchange to the progress of scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, Washington must not view countering China’s technological advancement as a substitute for investing in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-06-25/trumps-trade-war-wrong-way-compete-china&quot;&gt;major effort at home&lt;/a&gt;. The Trump administration’s repeated attempts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-00719-4&quot;&gt;cut budgets&lt;/a&gt; for the National Science Foundation and other government S &amp;amp; T funding are profoundly self-defeating at a time of intensified U.S.-Chinese tech competition. China’s technological advancement will challenge not only U.S. power but also the United States’ sense of itself as a global leader and innovator. This demands significant U.S. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-06-25/trumps-trade-war-wrong-way-compete-china&quot;&gt;domestic investment&lt;/a&gt; in S &amp;amp; T—in government research labs and private research institutions for certain, and perhaps in private companies directly. It will also require mobilizing the American people behind making significant improvements to the education, infrastructure, and immigration systems, which are sources of the country’s enduring strength. If there is one thing that U.S. policymakers can learn from the history of &lt;em&gt;ganchao&lt;/em&gt;, it is that the world still wants what the United States has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;JULIAN BAIRD GEWIRTZ is Academy Scholar at Harvard’s Weatherhead Center for International Affairs and the author of &lt;em&gt;Unlikely Partners: Chinese Reformers, Western Economists, and the Making of Global China&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, August 27, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Julian Baird Gewirtz</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2019-08-27/chinas-long-march-technological-supremacy</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/27/chinatech.jpg?itok=NjjQxRCc</image>
 <media:description>Signs advertising 5G and China Unicom go up in Shanghai, April 2019 - Aly Song/REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>The Roots of Xi Jinping’s Ambition to “Catch Up and Surpass”</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-08-29T14:09:20-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Diplomacy Can’t Solve All of Afghanistan’s Problems</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-08-26/diplomacy-cant-solve-all-afghanistans-problems</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of August 17, as over 1,000 guests danced at a wedding celebration in Dubai City, a hall in Kabul named after the Afghan elite’s favorite weekend getaway, a 23-year-old interloper detonated his suicide vest by the bandstand. The blast killed 80 people and wounded nearly 200 more, mostly from the Hazara ethnic group, followers of the Shiite sect of Islam predominant in that neighborhood of western Kabul. The groom and bride, who are both Shiite, miraculously survived. “I will never see happiness in my life again,” the groom, a tailor named Mirwais Elmi, told Afghanistan’s TOLOnews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the worst of the bloody events that have punctuated nine rounds of peace talks between U.S. and Taliban negotiators since July 2018. Ten days earlier, a Taliban suicide attack on a Kabul police station left 14 dead and 145 wounded. On the night of August 11, a joint U.S.-Afghan unit of the Khost Protection Force, a “counterterrorist” unit run by the CIA, captured and summarily executed 11 unarmed male civilians in the Zurmat district of Paktia Province, on Afghanistan’s eastern border with Pakistan. The victims were abducted at night while celebrating the holiday of Eid al-Adha and shot in the head at close range. On &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/25/magazine/afghan-war-casualty-report.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedLinks&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&quot;&gt;July 20 and 22&lt;/a&gt;, bombing raids by U.S. and Afghan Air Forces killed 12 civilians, including nomads and farmers in Badghis and Logar Provinces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what might have been a cruel parody of the origins of Afghanistan’s violence—but turned out to be an even crueler fact—the so-called Islamic State (or ISIS) based in Iraq and Syria issued a statement in Arabic (a language not spoken in Afghanistan) taking responsibility for the attack on the wedding and claiming it had been carried out by one “Abu Asim al-Pakistani,” whose very name seemed to mock the irrelevance of Afghanistan to its own people’s suffering. ISIS claimed that the wedding guests were “polytheists.” The government claimed that the victims in Zurmat were “Taliban.” The Taliban claimed the police station was a legitimate military target that civilians should stay away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bombings and “counterterrorist” operations by both the U.S. and Afghan governments take place under the “relaxed” rules of engagement set by President Donald Trump and about which he boasted in 2017, “We are not nation-building again. We are killing terrorists.” For the first time since the beginning of the war, U.S. and Afghan government forces have caused more civilian casualties this year than have the Taliban, according to the United Nations. And so it is hardly surprising that Afghans are not overly optimistic about an impending peace agreement between the United States and the Taliban. It is even less surprising that stalwarts of the U.S. national security establishment such as retired General and former CIA Director David Petraeus warn of the dangers of a “complete military exit from Afghanistan” and claim that “common sense dictates the U.S. must retain its own means to pressure extremist networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 18 years of “presence and pressure,” and as the U.S.-backed Afghan government continues to lose ground to the Taliban and ISIS massacres civilians in Kabul with impunity, the national security establishment’s version of “common sense” is to double down on failing policies. When you are in a hole, you should make a long-term commitment to digging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Leave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Petraeus and his colleagues are right to warn of the dangers of a withdrawal that is too abrupt. Trump’s rush to make Afghanistan’s peace process conform to the U.S. electoral calendar risks squandering whatever leverage the United States still has. Afghans rightly fear that an agreement may fail to guarantee the gains that some of them have made as a result of the “nation-building” efforts denigrated by Trump. But the impending withdrawal is a consequence of the situation on the ground in both Afghanistan and the United States, not the result of the peace effort. Trump’s impatience to withdraw both enables and threatens the prospect of peace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most important issues at stake in the negotiations have been left ambiguous, perhaps deliberately. Among them is whether the completion of the U.S. troop withdrawal is contingent on the implementation of a political settlement between the Afghan government and the Taliban. The sequence and interdependence of the troop withdrawal, cease-fire, and political settlement have yet to be clarified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any agreement is guaranteed to fall short of aspirations—but not because of the failures of negotiators or Trump’s determination to leave Afghanistan (which is shared by nearly all his rival presidential aspirants). Eighteen years of U.S. military strategy have failed to produce stability or eliminate terrorism. There is no reason to believe that a longer time horizon will generate better results. That a U.S.-Taliban agreement may fail to deliver the very same outcomes that have eluded the U.S. military for nearly two decades is not an indictment of the negotiations but rather a reflection of the failure of previous military strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;That a U.S.-Taliban agreement may fail to deliver the very same outcomes that have eluded the U.S. military for nearly two decades is not an indictment of the negotiations but rather a reflection of the failure of previous military strategies.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eventual U.S.-Taliban agreement resulting from nine rounds of negotiations in Doha could still present the best chance to achieve basic U.S. goals, reduce violence in Afghanistan, and make more effective counterterrorist measures possible. The Taliban have agreed to negotiate with the Afghan government and other Afghan political forces over a cease-fire and a political settlement once the question of the U.S. troop withdrawal is settled. Norway is actively working to organize those negotiations, which are expected to start in Oslo in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome of the peace process is less certain than the foreordained failure of military solutions. Multiple “peace processes” over the last 40 years of war in Afghanistan have led to reconfigurations of hostilities. Peace did not greet the end of the Soviet intervention in Afghanistan after the 1988 UN-sponsored Geneva Accords (and the subsequent demise of the Soviet Union itself). The United States supported the mujahideen in their opposition to any negotiation with the Moscow-supported “Kabul regime,” and regional states, above all Pakistan, intensified proxy wars in Afghanistan to ward off perceived threats from geopolitical rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Fragile Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a scenario could repeat itself. Without both an internal political system that accommodates major power holders and a minimal international consensus on the political and security dispensation in Afghanistan, Afghan and international actors can easily return to destabilizing what remains the poorest country in Asia, where over half the population lives below an already very low poverty line and young men are vulnerable to recruitment by armed groups. It is important to understand that for many in the region, a U.S. military and intelligence presence in Afghanistan represents a threat on a par with terrorism. Whatever the substance of the impending peace deal, Afghanistan will not become a stable base for American forces, since those who oppose their presence will continue to provoke conflict that weakens the state and provides entry points for terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much also depends on how the Taliban reconcile with their enemies in the government in Kabul. Will the Taliban retreat from a desire to reestablish their “Islamic Emirate” on the ruins of Afghanistan’s fragile Islamic republic? While the Afghan government and the diverse coalition that supports the current constitutional order seem prepared to accommodate some Taliban demands, a broad national and international consensus has emerged for preserving the social and political gains of the Islamic republic, including the expansion of rights and opportunities for women. In recent discussions, Chinese, Russians, Iranians, and Pakistanis have all asserted that an Islamic emirate remains a redline for them. Building such an international consensus in favor of the peace process has been one rare diplomatic success for the administration: the United States has issued joint statements supporting the process with China, Russia, Pakistan, and the European Union. All these actors, as well as Iran, will be invited to witness the announcement of any U.S.-Taliban agreement and the subsequent&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;opening of negotiations between the Afghan government and the Taliban in Oslo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success in these negotiations, coupled with the support of a broad international coalition, should strengthen and focus Kabul’s fight against the Islamic State Khorasan, the branch of the international jihadi group that has gained strength in the north and east of Afghanistan. A government in Kabul no longer distracted by the Taliban’s cross-border insurgency could become a more effective partner in international efforts to stamp out ISIS in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stability and a modicum of peace in Afghanistan would also require international cooperation to connect the landlocked country to world markets in coordination with various ambitious international development initiatives, including China’s Belt and Road Initiative, the Indo-Iranian-Afghan development of the Iranian port of Chabahar and related land routes to Afghanistan and Central Asia, and several pipeline and energy transmission projects supported by the United States. The Trump administration’s policy of confrontation with many of the powers involved in these projects augurs poorly for the future of any Afghan peace agreement, but future administrations may change course. The odds of a positive outcome stemming from the negotiating table are not great, but they are better than the odds that the United States will succeed militarily after nearly two decades of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;BARNETT R. RUBIN is a Senior Fellow and Associate Director of the Center on International Cooperation at New York University and former Senior Adviser to the U.S. State Department’s Special Representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan and the UN Special Representative of the Secretary-General for Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, August 26, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Barnett R. Rubin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/afghanistan/2019-08-26/diplomacy-cant-solve-all-afghanistans-problems</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/26/afghanistan1.jpg?itok=3Y9O3Y8n</image>
 <media:description>A U.S. Marine at an outpost near Kunjak in southern Afghanistan, February 2011 - Finbarr O&amp;#039;Reilly/REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>But Neither Can U.S. Troops</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-09T09:31:08-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Myth and Meaning of Resistance</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/europe/2019-08-23/myth-and-meaning-resistance</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Seventy-five years ago, Charles de Gaulle, leader of France’s provisional government, returned to Paris. For four years, he had lived in exile in London. Now he made his way through an exuberant crowd at the Hôtel de Ville, the site at which France’s earlier revolutions and republics were consecrated, greeting the leaders of the nation’s resistance movements. De Gaulle had not planned or rehearsed the speech he gave on this occasion, but it was perhaps his greatest. “Do not let us hide this deep and sacred emotion,” he said. “There are moments that go beyond each of our poor little lives. Paris! Paris outraged! Paris broken! Paris martyred! But Paris liberated! Liberated by itself, liberated by its people with the help of the armies of France, with the support and the help of the whole of France, of France that is fighting, of France alone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Gaulle’s words cemented an idea of the French Resistance that has endured—that of a rebellious nation united under his command. Over the decades that followed, historians burnished the fairy tale that the general offered to a grateful and exhausted nation. As Paris prepares to celebrate the 75th anniversary of its liberation, the convenient myth and inconvenient truth of the Resistance bears revisiting, both for its own sake and for the parallels it offers in our own time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadows and Penumbras&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man now acclaimed as the leader of the Resistance began as the obscure leader of the Free France movement, a small and motley collection of civilians and soldiers. On June 18, 1940, in a broadcast that would later become famous and that gave the anti-Nazi movement its name, de Gaulle called upon the French to maintain “the flame of resistance.” At that moment, millions of panicked civilians and soldiers surged southward ahead of the German advance. Few citizens took the time to listen to a radio broadcast by an unknown French officer who seemed to have fled to safety across the Channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One remarkable exception was the entire male population of the tiny Breton island of Île de Sein. Upon hearing de Gaulle’s call, they took to their fishing trawlers and joined Free France in England. And in the weeks and months that followed, scattered others, alone or in groups, sought ways to resist. Some hailed from the military—for example, Henri Frenay, a founder of the clandestine movement and newspaper &lt;em&gt;Combat&lt;/em&gt;; others, from the academy, as was the case for a group of scholars and researchers who gathered around the Musée de l’Homme; and still others from the churches, led by Protestant pastors and a smattering of Jesuit priests. The traditional political parties were missing in action: the Communist Party, for example, paralyzed by the mutual nonaggression treaty between Nazi Germany and Soviet Russia, while leading socialist and radical figures had either been arrested or fled into exile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was in this rocky soil that the French Resistance took root. While the movement has a name, historians have nevertheless struggled to fully explain what it was, how it happened, and why it matters. The difficulty is hardly surprising given the clandestine and complex character of the Resistance. As to its nature, one leading French historian, Pierre Laborie, has more or less thrown up his hands. He observed that the Resistance is little more than a catch-all phrase, indicating “a web of intertwined engagements and singular paths that find their true meaning only in the collective dimension of action and in the solidarity formed through a shared experience. That experience was without peer for those who lived it and will remain in great part inaccessible and intransmissible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;While the French Resistance has a name, historians have nevertheless struggled to fully explain what it was, how it happened, and why it matters.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today a growing consensus among specialists holds that the Resistance was, as the French historian &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.persee.fr/doc/xxs_0294-1759_1996_num_50_1_3520&quot;&gt;Olivier Wieviorka&lt;/a&gt; puts it, a “minority movement whose perilous and multifarious existence long unfolded within an environment marked by the majority’s incomprehension and hostility.” Far from the Gaullist gloss of “the whole of France,” the Resistance was the work of the few. How few is not known. After all, how can one count heads in what was known as the “army of the shadows”? The official number of slightly more than 250,000, based on those men and women officially recognized as “&lt;em&gt;combattants volontaires de la résistance,&lt;/em&gt;” has by this light the same status as a medieval scholastic’s guess as to the number of angels who can dance on the head of a pin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that matter, how does one map these shadows? The criteria for official status as a &lt;em&gt;combattant&lt;/em&gt; privileged cloak-and-dagger activities like gathering information, sabotaging rail lines, printing clandestine newspapers, or assisting the escape of Jewish and foreign refugees. But others perhaps served in less obvious ways. François Marcot has suggested that a “penumbra” extends just beyond the shadows, formed by those who, say, painted Vs on walls or wrote plays that could be interpreted as calls to resistance. But is “penumbra” just another name for what the Swiss historian Phillipe Burrin calls accommodation? Most French, in countless ways in their everyday lives, came to terms with the German occupiers and their French collaborators. How should historians distinguish between such citizens, whatever their private feelings, and those who took risks of varying degree to express or act upon their objections?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Indignation to Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as historians take recourse to metaphors to capture the nature of the Resistance, they are confounded in their effort to offer a unified field theory for why some individuals chose to resist. It seems those who refused accommodation felt an urge to “&lt;em&gt;faire quelque chose&lt;/em&gt;.” But do what, and to what end? As another &lt;em&gt;Combat&lt;/em&gt; founder, Claude Bourdet, remarked, “To embark on that adventure, where the reasons for hope were hardly solid, was already a difficult choice. But you also had to have the sense that you could in fact achieve something real, do so something useful and effective. At the beginning, however, nothing seemed less certain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of certainty and means deterred even those who had already proved their courage and audacity. For example, when Bourdet approached the novelist and adventurer André Malraux, the man who had bravely fought alongside the Republicans in the Spanish Civil War sent him packing with the following words: “Come back and see me when you have money and weapons.” Even those who did act struggle to explain why they did so. In Marcel Ophüls’ celebrated and controversial documentary &lt;em&gt;The Sorrow and the Pity&lt;/em&gt;, Emmanuel d’Astier de la Vigerie declared that early resisters like himself “were basically maladjusted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historians dismiss d’Astier’s sally as empty bravado. Most resistance members were not social marginals but successful professionals who were widely respected and often married. They became outlaws not because they had nothing to lose but because they had everything to lose. Among those things was their dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dignity is one of those terms that social scientists cannot quantify. Time and again, however, it is the word chosen by those who resisted: indignation at France’s defeat and the Nazi occupation, indignation at the antidemocratic, anti-Semitic, and anti-secular Vichy regime, and indignation at the passivity of most of their fellow citizens. This sentiment not only inspired the late diplomat and writer Stéphane Hessel to join Free France as a young man but also led him to write the best-selling pamphlet &lt;em&gt;Indignez-vous!&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Time for Outrage&lt;/em&gt;) as an old man of 93 in 2011. Hessel insisted that indignation was only a beginning, and a useless one at that, unless it led one “to construct something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Most resistance members were not social marginals but successful professionals who were widely respected and often married.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, then, resist? In practical terms, the choice hardly seemed to matter in the case of the France during World War II. Not only would France have been liberated without the Resistance but the Allied leaders mostly wished to be liberated from the obdurate and obstreperous leader of the Resistance. Just ask Dwight Eisenhower, who had planned to bypass Paris in his push eastward. A popular uprising in Paris on August 19 forced his hand. If only to placate de Gaulle, he agreed to send a French armored division to Paris in order to support the resisters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Gaulle’s peroration got the scene only partly right. French resisters and French soldiers &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; liberate Paris. But not all Parisians manned barricades or heaved Molotov cocktails. Some, as Simone de Beauvoir reported, sunbathed along the Seine or cast their fishing lines while others, cradling rifles, crouched behind the river’s embankments. Moreover, most Parisians were less outraged than out of gas, both literally and metaphorically, having spent four years foraging for scarce food and fuel. Finally, as residents of devastated cities like Caen or Le Havre recall, Paris was not at all broken but gloriously intact. The Champs-Elysées that welcomed the French resisters in 1944 had not at all changed from the one that hosted the German troops in 1940.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for building something new after the liberation, the Resistance again fell short. In a radio address, Albert Camus, the young and dashing editor of &lt;em&gt;Combat&lt;/em&gt;, declared that “having started with resistance, the French want to finish with revolution.” Rather than a revolution, though, there was a resurrection. The Fourth Republic, a carbon copy of the unlamented and uninspiring Third Republic, replaced the Provisional Government. The postwar government did nationalize some banks and industries, and it passed some progressive social legislation, but these reforms were driven by the revived political parties, which paid lip service, then mostly put paid, to the ideals of the Resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Resister’s Mystique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the Dreyfus Affair, the French intellectual Charles Péguy once tried to measure the distance between the early idealism and later pragmatism of the movement in which he took a leading role. “&lt;em&gt;Tout commence en mystique&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;et finit en politique&lt;/em&gt;,” he said. He might have said the same of the French Resistance: everything began in mystique and ended in politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the true legacy of the Resistance is not easily measured. Women played an important role in the Resistance, and although they may not have ultimately made the difference in liberating France from the Germans, their work certainly helped to liberate the French from gender stereotypes, and in so doing, to liberate an entire category of human beings. By dynamiting deeply entrenched cultural and economic obstacles, women won the right to vote in 1945. French Jews, stripped of their rights and often their citizenship by the collaborationist regime in Vichy, played a vital role in the resistance movement. Indeed, foreigners from nearly every part of Europe filled the movement’s ranks, literally embodying the universalist claims of the French Revolution of 1789.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the Resistance lends itself to a certain kind of liberation theology. Not the sort, mind you, that was all the rage in South America half a century ago—rather, one that reminds us that the space between knowing and acting cannot be fully measured or plumbed. We can’t fully explain those men and women who acted despite the vast asymmetry between their paltry means and principled ends. But they inspire boundless respect, reinforcing our faith that in dark times, there will always be carriers of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early resister, Roger Stéphane, acknowledged that while his decision to engage was absurd, “it was by such absurdities that we restored our dignity as men.” For the realists, the 75th anniversary of the liberation of Paris is thus the occasion to recall that what begins in mystique almost always (and necessarily) ends in politics. Idealists might take away a different, if more elusive lesson—namely, that any politics worth the name does not lose sight of the mystique that gave it birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROBERT ZARETSKY is a professor of modern French history at the Honors College, University of Houston, and the author of &lt;em&gt;Catherine &amp;amp; Diderot: The Empress, The Philosopher, and the Fate of the Enlightenment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, August 23, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Robert Zaretsky</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/europe/2019-08-23/myth-and-meaning-resistance</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/23/rsz_france.jpg?itok=pArFUjZq</image>
 <media:description>French President Emmanuel Macron attends a ceremony in front of the statue of Charles De Gaulle in Paris, May 2018 - Etienne Laurent/REUTERS</media:description>
 <subtitle>What Drove France’s Army of Shadows?</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-09-12T18:02:40-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Gangs of El Salvador</title>
    <link>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/el-salvador/2019-08-22/gangs-el-salvador</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;At 11:56 am on December 18, 2015, seven Salvadoran gang leaders got on a conference call. Some of them dialed in from prison, others from the streets. Among the subjects they covered that night was a hit list of eight people. Before they carried out the murders, the gangsters on the outside needed approval from those on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deliberations began just 19 minutes into the conversation. The first potential victim, according to the indictment filed by Salvadoran prosecutors, was the father of an alleged cooperating witness. A few minutes later, he was given a “green light,” gang lexicon for condemned to death. Other victims followed: one gang member “for not adapting,” another for “snitching,” a woman for being what the gang called “gossipy.” By the time they had finalized the hit list, one hour, 25 minutes, and 44 seconds had passed since the discussion of the first homicide began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation, which was captured as part of a sprawling indictment of dozens of gang leaders,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is important, not just because eight people may have died as a result of it but because it forms part of the violent mosaic of El Salvador. In 2018, the country had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightcrime.org/news/analysis/insight-crime-2018-homicide-roundup/&quot;&gt;51 murders&lt;/a&gt; per 100,000 people, more than ten times the U.S. rate. Thanks in large part to endemic violence, citizens of El Salvador, together with those of the other countries in Central America’s so-called Northern Triangle, Guatemala and Honduras, have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/stats/sw-border-migration/usbp-sw-border-apprehensions&quot;&gt;accounted for 75 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all undocumented U.S. border apprehensions in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As debates over Central American migration have grown increasingly divisive in the United States, U.S. policymakers have sought to find ways to address its root causes. Perhaps no cause has loomed larger than endemic gang violence: over the past few years, leading experts on violence have studied whether El Salvador (and, by extension, Honduras and Guatemala) can adopt the types of gang-intervention programs that have proved so successful in U.S. cities such as Boston and Oakland, California. Their response, after a yearlong &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdf.usaid.gov/pdf_docs/PA00TR24.pdf&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and made public earlier this year, was a resounding maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a frustrating result. As Thomas Abt—a senior research fellow at the Harvard Kennedy School, former prosecutor, and former Obama administration Justice Department official—notes in his recent book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Bleeding-Out-Devastating-Consequences-Violence/dp/1541645723&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bleeding Out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the United States has seen an unprecedented drop in homicides since the early 1990s, thanks in part to the effectiveness of violence-prevention programs in a number of U.S. cities. We are, it seems, finally beginning to understand what causes gun violence and how to prevent it. Abt thinks that the United States can go much further, and wrote the book as a kind of memo to local and national policymakers. But applying these lessons in countries such as El Salvador may require more systemic changes—and a more sophisticated approach to gang violence—than what we have seen so far in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FOCUSED DETERRENCE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USAID El Salvador study was inspired by the success of a U.S. gang-intervention strategy known as “focused deterrence.” This strategy builds on the insight that, as Abt writes in &lt;em&gt;Bleeding Out,&lt;/em&gt; “murder and mayhem sticks in and around discrete people, places, and things.” In other words, the vast majority of violence is concentrated in a few areas and among a tiny fraction of the population. Authorities should therefore focus on reducing homicides block by block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focused deterrence was pioneered in Boston in the early 1990s, when police, communities, and Harvard Kennedy School wonks started working together to reduce gun violence in high-crime areas. By collecting and analyzing data and intelligence, the police and wonks were able to identify the most likely shooters and shooting victims in an area (often they were the same people). Then, police and community members organized face-to-face meetings. The community provided the carrot, offering targeted individuals “assistance and support,” which in the best of circumstances are social and economic pathways out of the violent spirals. The police provided the stick. As Abt writes, they tell “group members that they know they are involved in violence and it must stop. If it continues, law enforcement will come down not just on them as individuals but on their entire group.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, this approach has proved remarkably effective. Between 1996 and 1998, Boston saw a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncjrs.gov/pdffiles1/nij/188741.pdf&quot;&gt;63 percent reduction&lt;/a&gt; in youth homicide. And after Oakland adopted a focused deterrence strategy, its homicide rate dropped 32 percent between 2012 and 2017. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/USAID-2016-What-Works-in-Reducing-Community-Violence-Final-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 review&lt;/a&gt; of 30 crime- and violence-reduction programs, Abt and Christopher Winship, a Harvard-based sociologist, found that “focused deterrence” had “the largest direct impact on crime and violence.” And with help from the National Network for Safe Communities (NNSC), the John Jay College–based project that headed up the El Salvador study, focused deterrence has been applied in over 30 cities across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fa-stage-files.s3.amazonaws.com/styles/large-crop-landscape/s3/images/articles/2019/08/22/rts1g93c_2.jpg?itok=pmLzTbWO&quot; alt=&quot;MS-13 gang members arrive at a prison in Zacatecoluca, El Salvador, October 2017&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;MS-13 gang members arrive at a prison in Zacatecoluca, El Salvador, October 2017 - Jose Cabezas / Reuters&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TESTING THE MODEL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the El Salvador study was to evaluate whether focused deterrence would work in one of the most homicidal places on earth outside of a war zone. Yet, as its lead researchers noted, focused deterrence depends on three pillars: outside experts, the local community (which must establish strong norms around nonviolence), and law enforcement. All of these actors must have legitimacy—especially the police, who need to carefully select and approach their targets so as not to provoke a backlash from the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In El Salvador, all three pillars are weak or absent. For nearly two decades, Salvadoran law enforcement has employed a so-called Mano Dura (Hard Line) security policy, rounding up and incarcerating suspected gang members en masse. This has eroded police-community relations and public confidence in the system. What’s more, in recent years police have been implicated in dozens of &lt;a href=&quot;https://foreignpolicy.com/2019/07/06/el-salvadors-tough-policing-isnt-what-it-looks-like/&quot;&gt;extrajudicial executions&lt;/a&gt; of suspected gang members, destroying their claim to be fair arbiters of justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, similarly, few community norms around nonviolence. Although nearly 30 years have passed since the end of El Salvador’s brutal civil war, conflicts are still regularly resolved through violence. Where gang violence is not prevalent, vigilante justice is. And domestic violence is a perennial problem: on average, &lt;a href=&quot;http://observatoriodeviolencia.ormusa.org/boletinas/2018-0506_BOLETINA_VG.pdf&quot;&gt;18 criminal complaints&lt;/a&gt; about violence against women are filed every day, but only five percent of them are ever resolved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religious communities—some Catholic, but mostly evangelical—are the only stable institutions that &lt;a href=&quot;https://lacc.fiu.edu/research/the-new-face-of-street-gangs_final-report_eng.pdf&quot;&gt;offer an escape&lt;/a&gt; from gang life. Gangs typically kill members who try to leave but make an exception for those who find religion. Yet even this exit strategy is fraught with danger: as I have found in my own research, gangs monitor their former members, killing those who commit to religion but slip back into alcohol and drug use. And they never forgive members of rival gangs, regardless of whether they join a church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Can focused deterrence work in one of the most homicidal places on earth?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while El Salvador has high-quality gang investigators, it lacks innovative violence-reduction researchers. There are, quite simply, no local scholars who delve into what is politically perilous territory. In the land of Mano Dura, those who talk about an alternative risk getting burned—not just by a vengeful state but by the bloodthirsty gangs themselves.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DEALING WITH ORGANIZED VIOLENCE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Bleeding Out,&lt;/em&gt; Abt argues that violence-reduction strategies should steer clear of working with gangs. “By focusing on group-oriented violence, not the group itself,” he writes, “the strategy can pacify gangs while draining them of their status, power, and reason for existence.” In the United States, this approach makes sense. Gangs are less organized, violence more diffuse. In El Salvador, however, the gangs are a grade more hierarchical, a level more sophisticated, and a lot more violent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But might it still be possible to focus on the worst actors? The authors of the USAID report determined that a small part of the population—between 0.34 percent and 0.9 percent—was responsible for a disproportionate amount of the violence. They recommended that any program bring “the capacities of law enforcement, community, and service providers to bear on the behavior of [these] several hundred people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would presumably include the gang members who participated in the December 18, 2015, conference call. One of them was eventually arrested in Guatemala and &lt;a href=&quot;https://elperiodico.com.gt/nacion/2016/10/19/entregan-a-la-pnc-salvadorena-a-mongo-internacional-lider-salvatrucha-capturado-anoche-en-jutiapa/&quot;&gt;returned&lt;/a&gt; to El Salvador to face trial for those and other crimes. But it’s unclear if there were any repercussions for the other six gang leaders, several of whom were already in jail. What’s more, the December 18 call was just one of 22 similar calls chronicled by authorities during a three-month period in which the gang authorized 180 homicides from prison. In another phone call, gang leaders in prison greenlit 24 homicides. Narrowing the focus under these circumstances, where so many people are so lethal, will be a much greater challenge. And changing the group dynamic of gangs such as these might be near impossible.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The strategies in the book are designed to address disorganized or loosely organized violence,” Abt told me during a telephone interview. “[But] a gang conflict in El Salvador tends to be much more structured than conflicts here in the United States.” Still, despite these differences, the USAID report concluded that focused deterrence could make “a positive contribution” in El Salvador, likening it to the other locales where the NNSC has worked. “This will take time and effort, including re-imagining the analysis of groups, invigorating improved approaches to coordination, and integration of partners previously excluded from the conversation,” they wrote. “Yet all of these are tasks that are typical of any city choosing to adapt a focused deterrence approach.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;In other words: Just stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;About the Author:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;STEVEN DUDLEY is Co-director, Co-founder, and Head of Research for Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean at Insight Crime. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, August 22, 2019 - 12:00am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>By Steven Dudley</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/articles/el-salvador/2019-08-22/gangs-el-salvador</guid>
 <image>http://local2-devd7.foreignaffairs.com/s3/files/styles/ipad_rss_export_tablet_1x/s3/images/articles/2019/08/22/rtr30pjo.jpg?itok=mJ0uJiY2</image>
 <media:description>Members of the 18th Street gang at a prison mass in Izalco, near San Salvador, April 2012 - Ulises Rodriguez / Reuters</media:description>
 <subtitle>American Cities Reduced Violence—Will the Same Strategies Work in the Northern Triangle?</subtitle>
 <updated>2019-08-26T09:35:17-04:00</updated>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
